布鲁斯: 雷切尔，我看看
BRUCE: Rachel, let me see.
-我能看看吗？ -谁找的归谁，是我找到的
- Can I see? - Finders keepers. And I found it.
可这是我家的花园
In my garden.
谁找到归谁
Finders keepers.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
[木头断裂声]
[WOOD SNAPPING]
[砰]
[THUD]
布鲁斯？
Bruce?
妈妈！艾尔弗雷德先生！
Mom! Mr. Alfred!
[呜咽声]
[WHIMPERS]
[喊叫声]
[SCREAMING]
[有人远处喊叫]
[MEN SCREAMING IN DISTANCE]
做梦了，对吧
Did you have dream?
噩梦
Nightmare.
比这地方还糟吗？
Worse than this place?
[好了，吃饭了]
[MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE OVER P.A.]
他们要揍你
MAN [WHISPERS]: They are going to fight you.
-又来了？ -一直到把你杀了为止
- Again? - Until they kill you.
他们在早餐前能杀掉我吗？
Can they kill me before breakfast?
小子，你这是在地狱里
You are in hell, little man.
而我就是魔鬼
And I am the devil.
你不是魔鬼
You're not the devil.
只不过是我练身手用的
You're practice.
[呼噜声]
[GRUNTING]
[枪声]
[GUNSHOTS]
关禁闭
GUARD: Solitary.
-为什么？ -为了保护你
- Why? - For protection.
-我...我不需要保护 -那就保护了他们
- I don't need protection. - Protection for them.
[呻吟声]
[MEN GROANING]
进去
Get in.
杜卡德: 你如此疯狂地要向罪恶宣战 为此不惜进监狱
DUCARD: Are you so desperate to fight criminals...
...就是为了有足够的时间 一个个收拾他们
...that you lock yourself in to take them on one at a time?
事实上这次有...七个
Actually, there were seven of them.
我数的是六个，韦恩先生
I counted six, Mr. Wayne.
你怎么知道我的名字？
How do you know my name?
对于像布鲁斯.韦恩这样的人来说...
The world is too small for someone like Bruce Wayne to disappear...
...要想在这么小的世界里消失 不太容易
...no matter how deep he chooses to sink.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是杜卡德 我是拉.阿勒古尔的代言人
My name is merely Ducard, but I speak for Ra's al Ghul...
...他是令地下罪恶世界 闻风丧胆的人物
...a man greatly feared by the criminal underworld.
他将为你提供一条出路
A man who can offer you a path.
你为什么认为我需要出路？
What makes you think I need a path?
像你这样的人来到这 是经过精心挑选的
Someone like you is only here by choice.
你已经深入地了解了罪恶世界...
You have been exploring the criminal fraternity...
...但是无论有什么样的初衷...
...but whatever your original intentions...
...你最终都会感到迷失
...you have become truly lost.
那么拉.阿勒古尔又 能提供什么样的出路呢？
And what path can Ra's al Ghul offer?
一条为痛恨邪恶者提供的出路
The path of a man who shares his hatred of evil...
...愿意为公正献身者的出路
...and wishes to serve true justice.
影子军团出路
The path of the League of Shadows.
[笑声]
[CHUCKLES]
-你是治安维持会的？ -不，不是
- You're vigilantes. - No, no, no.
治安维持会的人是为了一己之满足
A vigilante is just a man lost in the scramble for his own gratification.
很容易丧失斗志，甚至连自己都陷于不义
He can be destroyed or locked up.
但是...如果你能够超越自我
But if you make yourself more than just a man...
把自己献身于某种信念
...if you devote yourself to an ideal...
如果任何人都无法阻止你
...and if they can't stop you...
你就会化身为某种永恒的东西
...then you become something else entirely.
什么东西？
Which is?
某种传奇，韦恩先生
Legend, Mr. Wayne.
明天你将被释放
Tomorrow, you will be released.
什么时候你厌倦了与一群小混蛋们周旋的时候 当你想成就一番事业的时候...
If you are bored of brawling with thieves and want to achieve something...
喜马拉雅东边山脚下生长着
...there is a rare blue flower that grows on the eastern slopes.
一种罕见的蓝色罂粟花 将向你召唤采一枝花
Pick one of these flowers.
你带着花爬到山顶...
If you can carry it to the top of the mountain...
...就能找到你所需要的东西
...you may find what you were looking for in the first place.
那么 我需要的是什么呢？
And what was I looking for?
答案你自己知道
Only you can know that.
[卡嗒声]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
你又绕回来 没错，你又绕回来啦
You turn back. You go back.
布鲁斯：我要找拉.阿勒古尔
BRUCE: Ra's al Ghul?
杜卡德：请稍等
DUCARD: Wait.
[乌尔都语]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[翻译] 你在寻找什么？
[TRANSLATING] What are you seeking?
我在寻找...
I seek...
...战胜非正义的方法
...the means to fight injustice.
用恐惧...
To turn fear...
...战胜恐惧的方法
...against those who prey on the fearful.
[乌尔都语]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
杜卡德 [翻译]: 为了掌控他人的恐惧...
DUCARD [TRANSLATING]: To manipulate the fears in others...
...你必须驾驭自己的恐惧
...you must first master your own.
你准备好了吗？
Are you ready to begin?
我....我快站不住了
I can... I can barely stand.
死亡并不会给你喘息的机会的
Death does not wait for you to be ready!
死亡没有同情心，也不会公正
Death is not considerate or fair!
为了准确无误 现在你必须面对死亡
And make no mistake, here you face death.
虎术
Tiger.
柔术
Jujitsu.
豹术
Panther.
你已经学到了这些武艺 但是这可不是当舞蹈跳着玩
You're skilled. But this is not a dance.
而且你心存恐惧
And you are afraid.
但不是我
But not of me.
告诉我，韦恩先生...
Tell us, Mr. Wayne...
...你惧怕的是什么？
...what do you fear?
[蝙蝠啸叫声]
[BATS SQUEAKING]
布鲁斯？
Bruce?
没事了没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
你会没事的
You'll be okay.
艾尔弗雷德： 要不要叫救护车，韦恩大人
ALFRED: Will we be needing an ambulance, Master Wayne?
托马斯：不必了，我可以给他接骨 然后带他去照个X光片子就行了
THOMAS: No, I'll set the bone and take him for an x-ray later.
艾尔弗雷德：那好，先生
ALFRED: Very good, sir.
-我很抱歉 先生 我已经... -托马斯：不必担心，他没事的
- I'm very sorry, sir. I've told... THOMAS: Don't worry. It's fine.
艾尔弗雷德: 摔得够呛吧，布鲁斯少爷
ALFRED: Took quite a fall, didn't we, Master Bruce?
托马斯: 到底是怎么摔下去的？
THOMAS: And why do we fall?
那儿摔倒的就从哪儿爬起来
So we can learn to pick ourselves up.
摔了下，小小的骨折而已
Just a little fall. It's just a small fracture.
托马斯:又梦见蝙蝠了？
THOMAS: The bats again?
你知道他们为什么袭击你吗？
You know why they attacked you, don't you?
-因为他们害怕你 -害怕我？
- They were afraid of you. - Afraid of me?
所有的生物都会感到恐惧
All creatures feel fear.
最厉害的动物也会？
Even the scary ones?
表面厉害的动物更会害怕
Especially the scary ones.
我有些东西要给你看
I got something to show you.
-你妈妈会喜欢？ -会的
- You think your mother will like them? - Yeah.
-是不是该起床了？ -也许吧
- I think it's time to get up. - Maybe.
托马斯:算了，还是继续躺着吧
THOMAS: No going back to bed.
这火车是你造的吗？
Did you build this train, Dad?
哥特城的人民对我们的家族有恩 但是这个城市正在经历痛苦
Gotham's been good to our family, but the city's been suffering.
不如我们富有的人们日子好过 所以我们建造了一条提供
People less fortunate than us have been enduring very hard times.
廉价服务的新的公共交通系统 重新把人们凝聚起来
So we built a new, cheap, public transportation system to unite the city.
而中心就是...
And at the center...
...韦恩大厦
...Wayne Tower.
布鲁斯:那是你工作的地方吗？ -不，我在医院工作
BRUCE: Is that where you work? - No, I work at the hospital.
我把公司交给 更善于经营的人去管理
I leave the running of our company to much better men.
-善于经营？ -就是...
- Better? - Well...
...就是对经营更感兴趣的人
...more interested men.
[歌声响起]
[PERFORMERS SINGING]
[管弦乐演奏]
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
[喘气声]
[GASPING]
咱们可以走了吗？
Can we go?
求你了
Please.
好吧，咱们走
Okay. Let's go.
-怎么了，布鲁斯？ -不不 是因为我
- What's wrong, Bruce? - No, no. It was me.
我想呼吸点新鲜空气
I just needed some fresh air.
你是不是觉得这个歌剧有点长？ 布鲁斯？
A little bit of opera goes a long way. Right, Bruce?
来吧 咱们走
Come on. Let's go.
钱包 首饰 赶快拿出来
Wallets, jewelry. Come on, fast.
托马斯:好的 切尔:快点
THOMAS: That's fine. CHILL: Fast.
别紧张
Take it easy.
给你
Here you go.
好的 好的
It's fine. It's fine.
拿去 走吧
Now just take it and go.
-我说了 把首饰也拿出来 拿出来 托马斯:嘿...
- I said, jewelry. THOMAS: Hey...
[枪声]
[GUNSHOT]
[玛撒大叫]
[MARTHA SCREAMING]
玛撒:托马斯
MARTHA: Thomas!
[枪声]
[GUNSHOT]
托马斯[细语]: 布鲁斯
THOMAS [WHISPERING]: Bruce.
没关系
It's okay.
你别害怕
Don't be afraid.
[照相机喀嚓作响]
[CHATTERING]
这是你父亲的吗？
Is this your father's?
没事了
It's okay.
过来
Come here.
穿上
There you go.
没事了
It's okay.
都过去了
雷波:戈登
LOEB: Gordon.
嘿
Hey.
好消息
Good news.
我们抓住他了，孩子
We got him, son.
你就放心吧
You're in excellent hands.
我们会帮你经管好企业的
We'll be watching the empire.
等你长大了 我们会把它好好交到你手里
When you grow up, it'll be waiting for you.
我想应该准备些晚饭了
I thought I might prepare a little supper.
-好吧 -艾尔弗雷德
- Very well. - Alfred?
-什么事，少爷？ -都怪我，艾尔弗雷德
- Yes, Master Bruce? - It was my fault, Alfred.
-是我让他们提前离开歌剧院的 -不...
- I made them leave the theater. - No.
-我要是不害怕的话... -这事跟你没关系
- lf I hadn't gotten scared... - It was nothing that you did.
全都是那凶手的错 都是他
It was him, and him alone.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
我想他们，艾尔弗雷德 我真的想他们
I miss them, Alfred. I miss them so much.
我也一样，布鲁斯少爷
So do I, Master Bruce.
我也一样
So do I.
杜卡德:你还为你父母的死感到自责吗？
DUCARD: And do you still feel responsible for your parents' death?
我的愤怒超过了我的自责
My anger outweighs my guilt.
来吧
Come.
你已经学会了用愤怒淹没自责
You have learned to bury your guilt with anger.
我来教你如何正确面对现实
I will teach you to confront it and to face the truth.
你知道如何战胜六个对手 我们可以教会你如何打败六百个敌人
You know how to fight six men. We can teach you how to engage 600.
你懂得如何潜伏
You know how to disappear.
我们可以教你如何隐身
We can teach you to become truly invisible.
隐身？
Invisible?
[阿伟]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
忍者都要明白隐身 最重要的是耐心和机敏
The ninja understands that invisibility is a matter of patience and agility.
[啊...]
[GRUNTING]
任何时候都要保持警惕
Always mind your surroundings.
忍者讲究实用小型炸弹
Ninjitsu employs explosive powders.
-当作武器？ -或者当作烟雾弹
- As weapons? - Or distractions.
戏剧性的骗术是很有效的手段
Theatricality and deception are powerful agents.
你必须超越你的对手对你的设想
You must become more than just a man in the mind of your opponent.
[我是冤枉的]
[MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
布鲁斯:他是谁？ -他是一个农夫
BRUCE: Who is he? - He was a farmer.
为了霸占邻居的土地 他变成了一个凶手
Then he tried to take his neighbor's land and became a murderer.
-现在被监禁了 -打算怎么处置他？
- Now he is a prisoner. - What'll happen to him?
正义，邪恶不能被宽恕
Justice. Crime cannot be tolerated.
要知道罪犯的所作所为 是对社会同情心的侮辱
Criminals thrive on the indulgence of society's understanding.
你父母的死并不是你的错
Your parents' death was not your fault.
而是你父亲的错
It was your father's.
你发火也没用 无法改变你父亲没有反抗的事实
Anger does not change the fact that your father failed to act.
-那个人手里有枪 -枪能阻止你反抗吗？
- The man had a gun. - Would that stop you?
我是受过训练的人
I've had training.
这跟训练毫无关系
The training is nothing!
主观决定一切
Will is everything!
付出行动的意愿
The will to act.
投降吧
Yield.
你并没有打败我
You haven't beaten me.
你在袭击我之前 脚下已经失控了
You have sacrificed sure footing for a killing stroke.
杜卡德:搓搓胸口
DUCARD: Rub your chest.
你的胳膊一会就暖和了
Your arms will take care of themselves.
你比你父亲要强壮
You are stronger than your father.
你并不认识我父亲
You didn't know my father.
但是我了解你内心的愤怒
But I know the rage that drives you.
这种无法抑制的愤怒 在你的内心郁结纠缠
That impossible anger strangling the grief...
...直到将你所爱的人的怀念...
...until the memory of your loved one is just...
...转化为你血液中的毒素
...poison in your veins.
总有一天，你会希望你所爱的人 从来都没有存在过...
And one day, you catch yourself wishing the person you loved had never existed...
...只有这样你才可以化解你的痛楚
...so you'd be spared your pain.
我并没有一直住在山里
I wasn't always here in the mountains.
我曾有个
Once, I had a wife.
相爱的妻子
My great love.
她离开了我
She was taken from me.
像你一样 我必须毫无选择地 面对这种残酷的事实...
Like you, I was forced to learn there are those without decency...
...必须学会无情的反击
...who must be fought without hesitation, without pity.
你的愤怒会带给你巨大的力量
Your anger gives you great power.
但是如果你不加以控制，他会毁掉你...
But if you let it, it will destroy you...
...我差一点就被毁掉
...as it almost did me.
-怎么阻止他？ -复仇
- What stopped it? - Vengeance.
这点对我无效
That's no help to me.
为什么 布鲁斯？
Why, Bruce?
你为什么不能为你的父母复仇?
Why could you not avenge your parents?
参加了听证会以后  您马上会普林斯顿去吗？
Will you be heading back to Princeton after the hearing, sir...
...或许我能说服您在这儿多住几天
...or can I persuade you to stay on for a day or two?
布鲁斯:我不会回去了
BRUCE: I'm not heading back at all.
艾尔弗雷德:你不喜欢那里？ -我很喜欢
ALFRED: You don't like it there? - I like it fine.
只是和以前的感觉不太一样
They just don't feel the same way.
-我已经把老爷的卧室给您收拾好了 -不必了
- I've prepared the master bedroom. - No.
我自己的房间就很好
My room will be fine.
艾尔弗雷德:恕我直言韦恩庄园属于您
ALFRED: With all due respect, sir, Wayne Manor is your house.
布鲁斯:不 艾尔弗雷德 它属于我父亲的
BRUCE: No, Alfred, it's my father's house.
-你父亲不在了 -这里是一座坟墓
- Your father is dead. - This place is a mausoleum.
如果依着我 我恨不能把这房子拆了
If I have my way, I'll pull the damn thing down brick by brick.
这栋房子，韦恩大人 荫庇了您的家族六代人了
This house, Master Wayne, has sheltered six generations of your family.
又不是你的家人，艾尔弗雷德 你干嘛那么在乎啊？
Why do you give a damn, Alfred? It's not your family.
我之所以在乎， 那是因为有一位好人他托付我
I give a damn because a good man once made me responsible...
...让我照顾他一生中...
...for what was most precious to him...
...最珍爱的一个人
...in the whole world.
道斯小姐打算开车送您去听证会
Miss Dawes has offered to drive you to the hearing.
他也许私下里有话要对你说
She probably hopes to talk you out of going.
布鲁斯:我难道要把我过去的一切 也和我的父母一同埋葬嘛？艾尔弗雷德
BRUCE: Should I just bury the past out there with my parents, Alfred?
我无法告诉你应该如何对待你的过去
I wouldn't presume to tell you what to do with your past, sir.
但是我们这些人都很关系 你如何对待您的未来
Just know that there are those of us who care about what you do with your future.
你还没有放弃我吗？
Haven't given up on me yet?
永远不会
Never.
艾尔弗雷德还把炼乳放在架子的顶层？
Alfred still keeps the condensed milk on the top shelf.
难道他没有注意到你已经长高了吗？
Hasn't he noticed you're tall enough to reach now?
我看是旧习难改了
Old habits die hard, I guess.
-不过这个方法从来没有阻止过咱们 -就是的
- Never used to stop us anyway. - No, it didn't.
你妈妈怎么样？
How's your mom?
她很怀念这里
She misses this place.
我也是
So do I.
是呀
Yeah.
不过已经物是人非了
But it's nothing without the people who made it what it was.
-现在这里就剩艾尔弗雷德 -还有你
- Now there's only Alfred. - And you.
-我不会留下来的，雷切尔 -你是来参加听证会的
- I'm not staying, Rachel. - You're just back for the hearing.
布鲁斯 我知道 谁也无法阻止你回来 我知道
Bruce, I don't suppose there's any way to convince you not to come.
听证会上必须...
Someone at this proceeding...
...有人代表我的父母
...should stand for my parents.
我们都很爱你的父母 布鲁斯
We all loved your parents, Bruce.
-切尔的所作所为是不可饶恕的 -那为什么你的上司要放走他
- What Chill did is unforgivable. - Then why is your boss letting him go?
在监狱里他和法尔科内 共用一部手机
In prison, he shared a cell with Carmine Falcone.
他听到了一些秘密 他想用此作为交换 提前出狱
He learned things, and he will testify in exchange for early parole.
雷切尔，这个人杀了我的双亲
Rachel, this man killed my parents.
我是永远无法忘记这一切的
I cannot let that pass.
我需要你的理解 雷切尔
And I need you to understand that, please.
好吧
Okay.
芬奇:经济大萧条对切尔先生 这样的工人打击最大
FINCH: The depression hit working people, like Mr. Chill, hardest of all.
他的罪行虽然骇人听闻 但是其犯罪的动机并非出于贪婪...
His crime was appalling, yes, but it was motivated not by greed...
...而是出于绝望
...but by desperation.
同时鉴于他已经在狱中服刑了十四年...
Given the 14 years served, as well as his extraordinary level of cooperation...
...加之这次他对地区检察官的通力配合...
...with one of this office's most important investigations...
...我们完全赞同提前解除他的刑期
...we strongly endorse his petition for early release.
法顿:切尔先生
FADEN: Mr. Chill?
切尔: 尊敬的大人...
CHILL: Your Honor...
...没有一天我不是生活在悔恨当中
...not a day goes by that I don't wish I could take back what I did.
是的 我是很绝望 像那时的许多人一样...
Sure, I was desperate, like a lot of people back then...
...但是这并不能改变我所作的一切
...but that don't change what I did.
法顿:我想今天有一位 韦恩家族的成员也在场
FADEN: I gather there is a member of the Wayne family here today.
他有话要说吗？
Has he got anything to say?
女记者1：他出来了 男记者1：他出来了 就是他
WOMAN 1: He's coming out the side! MAN 1: He's coming out the side, guys!
[叫嚷声]
[CLAMORING]
男记者2：布鲁斯.韦恩！
MAN 2: Bruce Wayne!
女记者2：乔！嘿！乔
WOMAN 2: Joe! Hey, Joe!
法尔科内向你问候
Falcone says hi.
[枪声]
[GUNSHOT]
[人们尖叫声]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
雷切尔：走吧，布鲁斯
RACHEL: Come on, Bruce.
我们别看了
We don't need to see this.
可我想看
I do.
雷切尔:地方检察官不可能明白
RACHEL: The DA couldn't understand why Judge Faden insisted...
...法官为什么要举行公开听证会
...on making the hearing public.
其实是法尔科内收买了他 使切尔暴露在公共场合
Falcone paid him off to get Chill out in the open.
也许我们还应该感谢他们呢
Maybe I should thank them.
-我不相信你真的这么想 -我要是真的这么想呢 雷切尔？
- You don't mean that. - What if I do, Rachel?
我父母应该得到公正
My parents deserved justice.
其实你在谈论的 不是公正 而是报仇
You're not talking about justice. You're talking about revenge.
-有时他们就是一回事 -不 它根本就不是一回事
- Sometimes, they're the same. - No, they're never the same.
公正是为了平息矛盾 而报仇是为了平息自己的愤怒
Justice is about harmony. Revenge is about you making yourself feel better.
-这就是为什么我们要建立公正的制度 -遗憾的是你的制度已经失效了
- It's why we have an impartial system. - Your system is broken.
[轮胎磨地声和汽车喇叭声]
[TIRES SCREECHING AND HORNS HONKING]
你真的在乎公正吗？ 还是只在乎你自己的痛苦？
You care about justice? Look beyond your own pain, Bruce.
这个城市已经腐朽堕落了
This city is rotting.
他们说起经济大萧条 好像已经是过去的历史
They talk about the depression as if it's history. It's not.
其实并非如此，这的一切比以往更糟
Things are worse than ever here.
法尔科内用罪恶和毒品 摧毁了我们的城市...
Falcone floods our streets with crime and drugs...
...每天都在制造乔.切尔 这样的亡命徒 你知道吗？
...preying on the desperate, creating new Joe Chills every day.
也许法尔科内并没有 亲手杀死你的父母...
Falcone may not have killed your parents, Bruce...
... 但他们摧毁了赖以生存的基础
...but he's destroying everything that they stood for.
你要是感谢他们就在这
You wanna thank him for that? Here you go.
大家都知道能在哪里找到这些为富不仁之人...
We all know where to find him. As long as he keeps the bad people rich...
...大家都近鬼神而远之
...and the good people scared, no one'll touch him.
像你父母一样站起来维护 正义的好人都没有了
Good people like your parents, who'll stand against injustice, they're gone.
当所有的好人都选择沉默的时候？ 这个城市还有什么希望...
What chance does Gotham have when the good people do nothing?
-我并不是你所谓的好人 雷切尔 -你是什么意思？
- I'm not one of your good people, Rachel. - What do you mean?
这么多年以来 我一直想杀死他
All these years, I wanted to kill him.
而现在却不同了
Now I can't.
你父亲会为你感到耻辱的
Your father would be ashamed of you.
你比报纸上看得高，韦恩先生
You're taller than you look in the tabloids, Mr. Wayne.
没带枪？真是对我的侮辱
No gun? I'm insulted.
-你托人带一封感谢信就行了 -我不是来表示感谢的
- You could've just sent a thank-you note. - I didn't come here to thank you.
我要让你知道 并不是所有哥特人都惧怕你
I came to show you that not everyone in Gotham's afraid of you.
只有认识我的人才怕我，孩子
Only those who know me, kid.
你看看吧 这儿有两位市议院的官员...
Look around you. You'll see two councilmen...
...一位众议院官员 几位警官...
...a union official, couple off-duty cops...
...还有一位法官
...and a judge.
现在我可以毫不犹豫地 把你的脑袋轰掉
I wouldn't have a second's hesitation of blowing your head off in front of them.
就当着他们的面，这就是你无法企及的能量
Now, that's power you can't buy.
这就是你恐惧的来源
That's the power of fear.
我并不惧怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
那是因为你以为自己 没有什么怕失去的
Because you think you got nothing to lose.
可惜你想得不仔细
But you haven't thought it through.
你没有考虑到 你那在市检察院工作的女友
You haven't thought about your lady friend in the DA's office.
还有你的老管家 嘣
You haven't thought about your old butler. Bang!
来自你们那个世界的人...
People from your world...
...有太多害怕失去的东西
...have so much to lose.
你以为 一位你的妈妈爸爸被杀了...
Now, you think because your mommy and your daddy got shot...
...你就了解人生的残酷 其实你还差得远
...you know about the ugly side of life, but you don't.
你还不知道什么叫做绝望
You've never tasted desperate.
你是布鲁斯.韦恩 哥特城的王子
You're... You're Bruce Wayne, the prince of Gotham.
千里之外你才体会得到 无人知晓的滋味
You'd have to go 1000 miles to meet someone who didn't know your name.
所以你不要带着你的愤怒到这里来 以此证实你的能力
So don't come here with your anger, trying to prove something to yourself.
这个世界你永远无法了解
This is a world you'll never understand.
因为你无法了解...
And you always fear...
...所以你才会恐惧
...what you don't understand.
就这样
All right.
好，我得这么说 你有种，小子
Yeah, you got spirit, kid. I'll give you that.
比你老子有种
More than your old man anyway.
在牢里 切尔告诉我说 那天晚上他去杀你父母的时候
In the joint, Chill told me about the night he killed your parents.
你父亲乞求他饶命
He said your father begged for mercy.
乞求
Begged.
像一条狗一样
Like a dog.
应该多给点他小费
Should've tipped better.
-这是干嘛？ -买你的外套
- For what? - Your jacket.
好吧
Okay.
嘿嘿嘿 把它给我 这件外套挺不错的
Hey, hey, hey. Let me have it. It's a nice coat.
别让人看见你穿它
Be careful who sees you with that.
-他们不会放过我 -谁呀？
- They're gonna come looking for me. - Who?
布鲁斯:所有人
BRUCE: Everyone.
这外套....
It's...
真不错
It's a nice coat.
杜卡德:当你生活在罪犯当中 你会不会开始同情他们？
DUCARD: When you lived among the criminals, did you start to pity them?
布鲁斯:当我第一次为了 不被饿死而偷窃的时候，是的
BRUCE: The first time I stole so that I wouldn 't starve, yes.
我失去了许多 判断对与错的能力
I lost many assumptions about the simple nature of right and wrong.
当我四处旅行的时候...
And when I traveled...
...我体会到了那种在罪恶面前的恐惧感...
...I learned the fear before a crime...
...以及犯罪后的快感
...and the thrill of success.
[站住，不许动...]
[MAN SHOUTING IN MANDARIN]
布鲁斯:但是我从未变成他们中的一员
BRUCE: But I never became one of them.
[长官，他不说他的名字]
[OFFICER 1 SPEAKING MANDARIN]
我才不管你叫什么名字呢 你就是一个罪犯
OFFICER 2: Fool. What do I care what your name is? You're a criminal.
[我不是罪犯]
[SPEAKING MANDARIN] I'm not a criminal
那你去跟这些货物的主人说吧 [韦恩企业，中国制造]
OFFICER 2: Tell that to the guy who owned these.
杜卡德:周游世界之后 你了解了罪犯的心理...
DUCARD: You've traveled the world to understand the criminal mind...
...并且战胜了内心的恐惧
...and conquer your fears.
但是罪犯并不可怕
But a criminal is not complicated.
真正可怕的是你的内心
And what you really fear is inside yourself.
你惧怕你内心的能量
You fear your own power.
惧怕你的愤怒...
You fear your anger...
...它会驱使你做出 或伟大或可怕的事情
...the drive to do great or terrible things.
现在你必须开始心灵的旅程
Now you must journey inwards.
你已经准备好了
You are ready.
深呼吸
Breathe.
吸
在你的恐惧中呼吸
Breathe in your fears.
面对他们
Face them.
若想战胜恐惧 你必须化身为恐惧
To conquer fear, you must become fear.
在他人的恐惧中体会到乐趣
You must bask in the fear of other men.
人最惧怕的就是看不见的东西
And men fear most what they cannot see.
你要化作一种可怕的想法
You have to become a terrible thought.
一个幻影
A wraith.
化作一个意念
You have to become an idea!
去感受恐惧蒙蔽了你的意识
Feel terror cloud your senses.
感受它扭曲的力量
Feel its power to distort.
控制一切的力量
To control.
并且相信这种力量属于你
And know that this power can be yours.
拥抱你内心最大的恐惧
Embrace your worst fear.
化作黑暗的一部分
Become one with the darkness.
[蝙蝠啸叫声]
[BATS SQUEAKING]
集中精力
Focus.
专著
Concentrate.
控制你的意识
Master your senses.
你不能留下任何破绽
You cannot leave any sign.
布鲁斯:我没有
BRUCE: I haven't.
真不错
Impressive.
[乌尔都语]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
杜卡德[翻译道] : 我们清除了你的恐惧
DUCARD [TRANSLATING]: We have purged your fear.
你现在可以统领这些武士了
You are ready to lead these men.
你已经准备好 变成影子军团的一员啦
You are ready to become a member of the League of Shadows.
但首先 你必须证明你对正义的信念
But first, you must demonstrate your commitment to justice.
[带上来]
[SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
不
No.
我不是刽子手
I'm no executioner.
同情心是你的弱点 而你的敌人却没有
DUCARD: Your compassion is a weakness your enemies will not share.
正因为如此，它才更重要
That's why it's so important.
正是他使我有别于敌人
It separates us from them.
你要面对的是罪恶 这个人是凶手
You want to fight criminals. This man is a murderer.
-这个人应该由法律制裁 杜卡德:由谁呢？
- This man should be tried. DUCARD: By whom?
腐败的官僚？
Corrupt bureaucrats?
罪犯根本就无视社会法律
Criminals mock society's laws.
这一点你比任何人都更了解
You know this better than most.
拉.阿勒古尔: 除非你做好准备...
RA'S A GHUL: You cannot lead these men...
...不惜一切战胜邪恶 否则你无法统领这些战士
...unless you are prepared to do what is necessary to defeat evil.
我统领他们所向何方呢？
And where would I be leading these men?
哥特城
Gotham.
作为哥特城之子...
As Gotham's favored son...
...你将是战斗在罪恶中心的 最理想的人选
...you will be ideally placed to strike at the heart of criminality.
-具体怎样？ -哥特城的末日已经来临
- How? - Gotham's time has come.
就像当年的君士坦丁堡或者罗马一样...
Like Constantinople or Rome before it...
...整个城市已经变成 苦难和非正义的温床
...the city has become a breeding ground for suffering and injustice.
它已经无可救药 必须寿终正寝了
It is beyond saving and must be allowed to die.
这是影子军团最重要的使命
This is the most important function of the League of Shadows.
为了这个使命 我们已经演练了数个世纪了
It is one we've performed for centuries.
哥特城...
Gotham...
...必须被摧毁
...must be destroyed.
这真是难以置信
You can't believe in this.
拉.阿拉古尔曾经 在我们最绝望的时刻救过我们
Ra's al Ghul rescued us from the darkest corners of our own hearts.
作为交换他要求我们不惜一切 去做必须的事情
What he asks in return is the courage to do what is necessary.
我会回到哥特城照此战斗...
I will go back to Gotham and I will fight men like this...
...但是我绝不能让 自己成为一名刽子手
...but I will not become an executioner.
布鲁斯
Bruce, please.
为了你自己 已经无法回头了
For your own sake, there is no turning back.
-你在干什么? -做我必须做的事，朋友
- What are you doing? - What's necessary, my friend.
[爆炸声]
[EXPLOSIONS]
[布鲁斯叫声]
[BRUCE SCREAMING]
我要告诉他 你救了他的命
I will tell him you saved his life.
韦恩少爷 你离开了有一段时间了
Master Wayne, you've been gone a long time.
-是啊 -看起来很时髦，就是
- Yes, I have. - You look very fashionable.
身上有些泥
Apart from the mud.
您这次打算在哥特城 多住一段时间吗？
Are you coming back to Gotham for long, sir?
能呆多久就呆多久
As long as it takes.
我要让哥特人明白...
I want to show the people...
...这个城市并不属于罪恶和腐败
...their city doesn't belong to the criminals and the corrupt.
大萧条时期  你父亲...
In the depression, your father nearly bankrupted Wayne Enterprises...
...倾其所有与贫穷斗争
...combating poverty.
他坚信他的榜样的力量可以激励 哥特的富人起来拯救他们的城市
He believed his example could inspire the wealthy of Gotham to save their city.
有用吗？
Did it?
某种程度上
In a way.
他们的死刺激了 那些富有的人采取行动
Their murder shocked the wealthy and the powerful into action.
我们必须打破 人们的这种冷漠态度
People need dramatic examples to shake them out of apathy.
以布鲁斯.韦恩的名义 做不到这点
I can't do that as Bruce Wayne.
我作为一个普通人...
As a man...
...是有血有肉的 会被忽略 会被轻易摧毁
...I'm flesh and blood, I can be ignored, destroyed.
但是如果作为一种象征....
But as a symbol...
作为一种象征的话
As a symbol, I can be incorruptible.
-会成为不朽 -什么象征？
- I can be everlasting. - What symbol?
某种常见...
Something elemental...
...但是有可怕的东西
...something terrifying.
我要是没理解错的话...
I assume that as you take on the underworld...
...你是要除暴安良？应该是 在危急时刻能够解救民众的象征
...this symbol is a persona to protect those you care about from reprisals?
你的意思是保护雷切尔？
You're thinking about Rachel?
实际上 我考虑的是我自己
Actually, sir, I was thinking of myself.
你告诉过别人我回来了吗？
Have you told anyone I'm coming back?
我还没想清楚...怎么样恢复你这个在 法律上已经死亡者的身份
I couldn't figure the legal ramifications of bringing you back from the dead.
-已死亡者？ -你失踪了七年
- Dead? - You've been gone seven years.
你已经申请我死亡了？
You had me declared dead?
事实上是厄尔干的 他接管了公司
Actually, it was Mr. Earle. He's taking the company public.
打算变卖你所占有的大额股份
He wanted to liquidate your majority shareholding.
那可是一大笔钱呢
Those shares are worth quite a bit of money.
幸亏当时我把一切都留给了你
Well, it's a good thing I left everything to you, then.
的确如此 先生
Quite so, sir.
你可以把那两劳斯莱斯轿车借去开 回来时要加满油
And you can borrow the Rolls, if you like. Just bring it back with a full tank.
在我看来 蔡司先生不仅对他人 而且对他自己都是一种威胁
In my opinion, Mr. Zsaz is as much a danger to himself as to others...
而监狱的环境恐怕并不利于 他的治疗和恢复
...and prison is probably not the best environment for his rehabilitation.
-克兰先生 -怎么，道斯小姐
- Dr. Crane. - Miss Dawes.
你真的认为像他这样凶残的杀手 不应该被送进监狱吗？
You think a man who butchers people for the mob doesn't belong in jail?
我可不会这么说 你说呢 道斯小姐？
I would hardly have testified to that otherwise, would I?
这已经是法尔科内的第三个杀手 经你证明精神失常...
This is the third of Falcone's thugs you've had declared insane...
...而转入你的精神病院的
...and moved into your asylum.
有组织的犯罪集团能够提供的 工作可能对他们颇有吸引力
The work offered by organized crime must have an attraction to the insane.
对腐败分子也一样吧？
Or the corrupt.
芬奇先生
Mr. Finch.
你应该过问一下道斯小姐身为检察院的代表...
You should check with Miss Dawes here...
...对我进行的影射和诬陷
...just what implications your office has authorized her to make. If any.
-怎么回事 雷切尔小姐？ -怎么回事 卡尔？
- What are you doing? - What are you doing, Carl?
芬奇:我在保护你呀
FINCH: Looking out for you.
法尔科内把半个城市都收买了
Falcone has half the city bought and paid for.
-算了吧 -你怎么能这么说呢？
- Drop it. - How can you say that?
因为我越是了解法尔科内 我就越担心的你安全
Because as much as I care about getting Falcone, I care more about you.
说得真动听
That's sweet.
[警笛声]
[SIRENS WAILING]
我们已经讨论过这事啦
We've been through all that.
[蝙蝠声]
[BAT SQUEAKING]
艾尔弗雷德:又一支蝙蝠
ALFRED: Blessed bat again, sir.
它们在庄园外面做了窝了
They nest somewhere in the grounds.
[蝙蝠声]
[BATS SQUEAKING]
我不能再帮忙了 这事已经有人盯上了
No more favors. Someone is sniffing around.
嘿，互助友爱吗 大夫
Hey, I scratch your back, you scratch mine, doc.
我还帮你收货呢
I'm bringing in the shipments.
我们是付钱的
We are paying you for that.
我对你帮忙比对钱更感兴趣
Maybe money isn't as interesting to me as favors.
我并不视此为你对我的威胁 法尔科内先生
I am more than aware that you are not intimidated by me, Mr. Falcone.
不过你也很清楚我为谁工作 等到他到达时...
But you know who I'm working for, and when he gets here...
他要来哥特城？
He... He's coming to Gotham?
是的
Yes, he is.
当他来时 他一定不希望听到...
And when he gets here, he's not going to wanna hear...
...你为了让你的小混混们少服刑 而置我们的计划于危险之地
...that you've endangered our operation just to get your thugs out of jail time.
-是谁让你不安？ -市检察院办公室的一个姑娘家
- Who's bothering you? - There's a girl at the DA's office.
-我们负责收买她 -她不吃这套
- We'll buy her off. - Not this one.
一个理想主义者？嗯？
Idealist, huh?
我们也有对付这种人的办法
Well, there's an answer to that too.
-我不想知道 -你应该知道
- I don't want to know. - Yes, you do.
不 我们这几个部门的增长 十分良好
MAN: No, we are showing very healthy growth in these sectors.
我认为托马斯.韦恩不会同意将武器生产...
I don't think Thomas Wayne would have viewed heavy-arms manufacture...
...作为企业基础产业的
...as a suitable cornerstone for our business.
不错，那是二十年前的事了 费德里克
Well, that's 20 years ago, Fredericks.
我认为二十年后的今天 我们应该允许...
I think after 20 years we can allow ourselves...
...不再以托马斯.韦恩的意愿为转移了吧
...to stop thinking about what Thomas Wayne would have done.
杰西卡:早上好 厄尔先生办公室
JESSICA: Good morning, Mr. Earle's office.
是的 他明天晚餐已经预订了
Yes, he's confirmed for the dinner tomorrow evening.
布鲁斯:早上好 我想见厄尔先生
BRUCE: Good morning. I'm here to see Mr. Earle.
您贵姓？
Name?
布鲁斯.韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
托马斯很可能也不同意 公司的股份上市
Thomas would probably not have taken the company public.
但是这却是我们这些 责任经营者打算做的事情
But that is what we, as responsible managers, are going to do.
杰西卡？
Jessica?
杰西卡？你在哪？
Jessica? Where are you?
布鲁斯:眼睛盯着球，然后... -怎么没人接电话？
BRUCE: Eye on the ball, and... - Why is no one answering the phone?
韦恩集团的电话，厄尔先生 我肯定他们还会再打过来的
It's Wayne Enterprises, Mr. Earle. I'm sure they'll call back.
布鲁斯？你不是死了吗？
Bruce? You're supposed to be dead.
对不起让你失望来了
I'm sorry to disappoint.
-我希望你看看这个文件 -你见过他了吗？
- I need you to take a look at this. - Have you seen him yet?
-谁？ -韦恩
- Who? - Wayne.
这可是特大新闻 他回来了
It's been all over the news. He's back.
厄尔:我已经无法阻止 这个庞大的机器了
EARLE: I'm sure you realize I can't stop the big machine.
太多的环节
Too many wheels turning.
-我们的股份就要上市了 -我明白
- We're going public. - I understand.
而且我会得到丰厚的回报的
And I'll be handsomely rewarded for my shares.
我来并不想干涉什么
I'm not looking to interfere.
-我只是来找工作 -哦？
- I am looking for a job. - Oh?
我只想了解一下 我家族的企业的情况
I just want to get to know the company that my family built.
你打算从哪儿开始呢？
Any ideas where you would start?
我对产品开发部比较感兴趣
Applied Sciences caught my eye.
福克斯的部门？
Fox's department.
我到时候通知他
I'll let him know you're coming.
你长得很像他―― 你的――父亲
You look like him. Your dad.
你是韦恩家族唯一的一员了
You're the only one left of the Wayne family.
你的根在这里 欢迎回家
This is where you belong. Welcome home.
环保程序 防御计划 还有消费产品
Environmental procedures, defense projects, consumer products.
全都处于样品阶段
All prototypes. None in production.
-没有进入生产环节 -一个都没有？
- On any level whatsoever. - None?
他们怎么向你介绍的？
What did they tell you this place was?
布鲁斯:他们什么都没跟我说
BRUCE: They didn't tell me anything.
厄尔当初派我来的时候 可是一字不差地这么跟我说的
Earle told me exactly what it was when he sent me down here.
无所事事
Dead end.
派我来就是避免 我在董事会惹麻烦
Place to keep me from causing the board any more trouble.
来吧
Come on.
-你曾是董事会成员？ -你父亲还在世的时候是
- You were on the board? - When your father ran things.
-你认识我父亲？ -是的
- You knew my father? - Oh, yeah.
我帮他造的火车
Helped him build his train.
到了
Here we are.
这是多功能防弹衣
Kevlar utility harness.
强吸力抓钩气枪
Gas-powered, magnetic grapple gun.
能够承重350磅的单纤维
The 350-pound test monofilament.
你父亲的火车很棒
Wonderful project, your dad's train.
直通韦恩大厦 水电公共设施到位
Routed it right into Wayne Tower, along with the water and power utilities.
把韦恩大厦变成了 哥特城的民间中心
Kind of made Wayne Tower the unofficial center of Gotham City.
当然，厄尔后来毁了它
Of course, Earle let it go to rot. Here we are.
这是诺迈司面料做的 步兵部队阻燃军服
Nomex survival suit for advanced infantry.
克福拉双织沙面料
Kevlar biweave, reinforced joints.
-耐撕扯？ -这东西连刀子都捅不破
- Tear-resistant? - This sucker will stop a knife.
-防弹吗？ -除非是正面射击
- Bulletproof? - Anything but a straight shot.
-为什么不投入生产？ -预算部认为...
- Why didn't they put it into production? - Bean counters didn't think...
...普通士兵的命不值300块
...a soldier's life was worth 300 grand.
那么，你为什么对这些感兴趣呢？ 韦恩先生
So, what's your interest in it, Mr. Wayne?
我想借用一下
I want to borrow it.
山洞探险
For spelunking.
山洞探险？
Spelunking?
是的 就是钻山洞
Yeah, you know, cave diving?
你借用这些盔甲 就为了钻山洞吗？
You expecting to run into much gunfire in these caves?
我不希望厄尔先生知道 我借走了这些东西
Look, I'd rather Mr. Earle didn't know about me borrowing...
韦恩先生...
Mr. Wayne...
...依我看...
...the way I see it...
...所有这些东西都属于你的
...all this stuff is yours anyway.
好吧，来试试吧
Okay. Give it a try.
太壮观了
Charming.
至少你梦能做个伴
At least you'll have company.
这肯定是韦恩庄园东南地最低的地基
This must be the lowest foundation of the southeast wing.
内战期间你的曾曾祖父 卷入了地下交通组织...
Your great-great-grandfather was involved in the Underground Railroad...
...秘密地把黑奴偷运到北方...
...secretly transporting freed slaves to the North...
...我猜这些洞穴就是干这个用的
...and I suspect these caverns came in handy.
艾尔弗雷德！快过来
Alfred! Come up here!
我在这看得很清楚 非常感谢，先生
I can see everything all right from down here, sir, thank you.
艾尔弗雷德:这头罩的主要部分 是在新加坡定制的
ALFRED: We order the main part of this cowl from Singapore.
布鲁斯:通过皮包公司？
BRUCE: Via a dummy corporation.
就是 然后呢 我们又从...
Indeed. And then, quite separately...
...中国定制了这些东西 你看
...we place an order to a Chinese company for these.
-我们再自己把他们拼装起来？ -一点没错
- Put it together ourselves. - Precisely.
因为订购的量会很大 所以要避免疑心
They'll have to be large orders, to avoid suspicion.
-有多大？ -我想大概十万件
- How large? - Say 10,000.
-哦，还有好多剩下来 -就是
- Well, at least we'll have spares. - Yes.
[警笛响]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[听不到的耳语]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[警察无线电里女人的声音]
[WOMAN CHATTERING OVER POLICE RADIO]
不想来点吗？
Don't suppose you want a taste.
会一直源源不断的 也许早晚有一天你会变聪明
I just keep offering, thinking maybe someday you'll get wise.
你这么做一点都不聪明福拉斯
There's nothing wise in what you do, Flass.
不过 吉姆 你不参与 令我们非常紧张
Well, Jimbo, you don't take the taste, makes us guys nervous.
我不是告密者
I'm no rat.
再说了 在这个地方 我又能到哪儿去告密呢？
In a town this bent, who's there to rat to anyway?
[笑声]
[LAUGHS]
蝙蝠侠:别转身
BATMAN: Don't turn around.
你是个好警察 不多的几个之一
You're a good cop. One of the few.
戈登:你想干什么？
GORDON: What do you want?
蝙蝠侠:卡曼.法尔科内每周都走私 成船的毒品进来
BATMAN: Carmine Falcone brings in shipments of drugs every week.
可是为什么没人逮捕他
Nobody takes him down. Why?
他已经收买了当权者
He's paid up with the right people.
那怎样才能制裁他？
What will it take to bring him down?
给法顿法官施压...
Leverage on Judge Faden...
...市检察院有人敢提起公诉
...and a DA brave enough to prosecute.
雷切尔.道斯
Rachel Dawes.
你是谁？
Who are you?
蝙蝠侠:认清我的标志
BATMAN: Watch for my sign.
就你一个吗？
You're just one man?
蝙蝠侠:现在不是两个？
BATMAN: Now we're two.
我们？
We?
不许动
Freeze!
到底是什么东西？
OFFICER: What the hell was that?
不过是个疯子
Just some nut.
今天想借什么？ 还是去钻山洞？
Well, what is it today? More spelunking?
不 去低空跳跃
No. Today it's BASE-jumping.
低空跳跃
BASE-jumping.
-就像跳伞一样吗？ -有点像
- That like parachuting? - Kind of.
你有那种分量很轻的面料吗？
Do you have any lightweight fabrics?
正好 有这种东西
You know, I think I have just the thing.
这叫做记忆面料 你听说过吗？
It's called memory cloth. Notice anything?
正常情况下很柔软..
Regularly flexible...
...一旦电流通过...
...but put a current through it...
-...分子就会重组 他就会变得坚硬 -你能把它做成什么形状？
...molecules realign, it becomes rigid. - What kind of shapes can you make?
我能把它裁剪成任何形状
Can be tailored to fit any structure based on a rigid skeleton.
做军服是不是太贵了?
Too expensive for the Army?
我想他们没试过把它推销给喜欢 钻山洞和低空跳跃的亿万富翁
I don't think they tried to market it to the billionaire, BASE-jumping crowd.
-听着 福克斯先生 -是的 先生
- Look, Mr. Fox. - Yes, sir?
要是你不愿意的话--
If you're uncomfortable...
韦恩先生 如果你不愿意 告诉我实情的话...
Mr. Wayne, if you don't want to tell me exactly what you're doing...
...那别人问我的时候 我也就用不着撒谎
...when I'm asked, I don't have to lie.
可是别把我当傻瓜
But don't think of me as an idiot.
着很合理
Fair enough.
那是什么？
What's that?
那个装甲车？
The Tumbler?
哦，你不会感兴趣的
Oh, you wouldn't be interested in that.
它是当临时桥梁用的
She was built as a bridging vehicle.
在冲突中 两辆转向车 就可以越过河流 架起缆绳
During combat, two of these would jump over a river, towing cables.
你一碰这个开关就打开了 然后就整个的弹起来
Over here on the throttle, flip that open and throttle up.
远远的跳出去-- 不行 等会
This will boost you into a rampless jump... Not now!
现在不要 先生
Not... Not now, sir.
电脑:点火系统解除
COMPUTER: Afterburner disengaged.
桥梁试验从来没有成功过...
We never could get the damn bridge to work...
...但是它弹跳得很好
...but this baby works just fine.
你觉得怎么样？
So, what do you think?
有黑色的吗？
Does it come in black?
我要你到码头来 星期四
I need you at the docks Thursday.
-有麻烦吗？ -我希望最后一趟...
- Problems? - I don't want any trouble...
-...别出任何娄子 -当然
...with the last shipment. - Sure.
据说市检察院里有人找你的麻烦
Word on the street is you got a beef with somebody in the DA's office.
-是吗？ -而且有一大笔钱...
- Is that right? - And that there's a fat prize...
...在等着有人处理此事呢
...waiting for anybody willing to do anything about it.
你想说什么？福拉斯先生
So, what's your point, Mr. Flass?
你见过那女孩吗？
Have you seen the girl?
福拉斯[无线电里]: 一个娇小可爱的检察院助理
FLASS [ON RADIO]: It's a cute little assistant D A.
难道你不认为事情有些棘手吗？
Don 't you think that's a little too much heat to bring down, maybe?
-即使是在这样的城市里 -不要低轨哥特城
- Even for this town. - Never underestimate Gotham City.
每天上下班都有人被抢
People get mugged coming home from work every day of the week.
有的时候-- 有的时候事情还会更严重一些
Sometimes... Sometimes things just go bad.
这与石墨的含量有关
It's a problem with the graphite, sir.
下一万件会更结实些
The next 10,000 will be up to specifications.
-至少这些价钱还打了折扣呢 -那倒是
- At least they gave us a discount. - Quite.
不过先生 我还是要提醒您 一定要避免头部先着地
In the meantime, sir, may I suggest you try to avoid landing on your head?
为什么选择蝙蝠呢 韦恩少爷
Why bats, Master Wayne?
因为蝙蝠吓着我
Bats frighten me.
现在轮到敌人恐惧了
It's time my enemies shared my dread.
福拉斯:这是什么？
FLASS: What is this?
继续干
Continue.
看着真不错
Looks fine out there.
这些小熊直接送到毒贩手里
The bears go straight to the dealers.
是的 那些兔子是送给 住在窄岛上的人的
Yeah, and the rabbits go to the man in the Narrows.
-有什么区别吗？ -你最好别打听 我的朋友
- What's the difference? - Ignorance is bliss, my friend.
你千万不要打听 那些危险人物的秘密
Don't burden yourself with these secrets of scary people.
[叫喊声]
[STEISS SCREAMS]
嘿 斯泰斯？
Hey. Steiss.
斯泰斯？
Steiss?
看什么呢？
MAN: What?
怎么会...
What the...?
[呼喊声]
[SCREAMING IN DISTANCE]
[枪声]
[GUNSHOTS]
我去看看
I better check it.
[喘息声]
[PANTING]
有麻烦了 你最好赶快走
There's a problem out here. You better bail.
[砰]
[THUD]
你在哪儿？
Where are you?!
在这
Here.
[叫喊声]
[SCREAMS]
[咕哝声]
[GRUNTING]
快开 该死
Take a ride. Oh, shit.
你到底是谁？
What the hell are you?
[玻璃打碎声]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
外套不错
Nice coat.
谢谢
Thanks.
别动
Hold it.
这就对了 你还是快跑吧
That's right, you better run.
[喊叫声]
[SCREAMS]
[电流沙沙声]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
法尔科内派他们来杀你
Falcone sent them to kill you.
-为什么？ -因为你对他造成了威胁
- Why? - You rattled his cage.
-这是什么？ -筹码
- What's this? - Leverage.
-做什么用？ -推动事态发展
- For what? - To get things moving.
你是谁？
Who are you?
和你一样的人
Someone like you.
给他们造成威胁的人
Someone who'll rattle the cages.
嘿 你没事吧
Ma'am? Everything okay?
-法尔科内的人? -有什么用？
OFFICER: Falcone's men? - Does it matter?
能把他绳之以法么？
We'll never tie him to it anyway.
我也没办法
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
那是什么？
What the hell is that?
给他松绑
Cut him down.
[哥特城邮报:蝙蝠教训犯罪集团头目] 雷波:决不允许
LOEB: Unacceptable.
我才不管他是什么复仇小组 守护天使...
Now, I don't care if it's rival gangs, Guardian Angels...
...还是什么救世军...
...or the goddamn Salvation Army...
...统统把他们清扫出街道和报纸的头条
...get them off the street and off the front page.
据说只有一个人或者说是某种生物
They say it was just one guy. Or a creature.
是个妈的穿戏服耍把戏的家伙
It was some asshole in a costume.
-说吧 -可是这个穿戏服的家伙确实给我们...
- Yeah? - This guy did deliver us...
...送来了一个大毒枭
...one of the city's biggest crime lords.
在我的城市里 哪个人也无权擅自执法
No one takes the law into their own hands in my city.
明白了吗？
Understand?
雷切尔:掩盖不住了 芬奇:不过还有法顿法官
RACHEL: No way to bury it now. FINCH: There's still Judge Faden.
-我搞定法顿法官了 -可那个闹得沸沸扬扬的蝙蝠怎么办？
- I've got Faden covered. - What about this bat they babble about?
就算那些家伙说 被一个大蝙蝠袭击了...
Even if these guys will swear to being thrashed by a giant bat...
...可是我们还是在现场抓住了法尔科内
...we've got Falcone at the scene.
毒品 指纹 货单 他把证据都给我们准备好了
Drugs, prints, cargo manifests. This bat character gave us everything.
好吧 那咱们就干吧
Okay. Let's do it.
-蝙蝠是夜行动物 艾尔弗雷德:不过即使是...
- Bats are nocturnal. ALFRED: Bats may be.
身家亿万的花花公子 下午三点也不起床也太过分了
But even for billionaire playboys, 3:00 is pushing it.
我担心的是过双重生活的代价
The price for leading a double life, I fear.
你的戏剧行动确实引人注意
Your theatrics made an impression.
布鲁斯:戏剧性和出其不意...
BRUCE: Theatricality and deception...
...确实是有力的武器 艾尔弗雷德 这是个良好的开端
...are powerful weapons, Alfred. This is a good start.
如果这些伤痕只是一系列伤痕的开始...
If those are to be the first of many injuries to come...
...你最好找个聪明的借口
...it would be wise to find a suitable excuse.
比方说打马球
Polo, for instance.
可我不会打马球 艾尔弗雷德
I'm not learning polo, Alfred.
奇怪的创伤 一种不存在的社交生活
Strange injuries, a nonexistent social life.
这会引起人们的兴趣...
These things beg the question...
...要琢磨布鲁斯是 如何消磨他的时间和金钱的
...as to what exactly does Bruce Wayne do with his time and his money.
像我这样的人通常会做什么？
What does someone like me do?
开跑车 泡电影明星
Drive sports cars, date movie stars.
买一些个非卖品
Buy things that are not for sale.
这些事情 韦恩少爷 您就假装您感兴趣...
Who knows, Master Wayne, you start pretending to have fun...
...也许某时你真的会感“性趣”
...you might even have a little by accident.
先生
MAN: Sir.
-我们有大麻烦了 -怎么？
- We have a situation. - All right.
昨晚海安巡警找到了 我们的一只货船...
The Coast Guard picked up one of our cargo ships last night...
...已严重损毁 所有船员失踪 估计已全部死亡
...heavily damaged, all crew missing, probably dead.
货船运载了一批试验武器
The ship was carrying a prototype weapon.
是一种微波发射器
It's a microwave emitter.
是为了 --为了沙漠战设计的--
It's designed for desert warfare, but it...
可是它好像被人...
It looks like somebody...
...给打开了
...turned it on.
它是用来蒸发对手的供水设施的
It uses focused microwaves to vaporize the enemy's water supply.
货船损毁很严重
The damage to the ship was catastrophic.
而武器本身....
The weapon itself is...
也失踪了
Missing?
是
Yeah.
韦恩先生
MAN: Mr. Wayne.
真是好车
Nice car.
你应该见识见识我另一辆车
You should see my other one.
他干了警察干不了的事
WOMAN: He's done something the police never have.
可也不改擅自执法
MAN: You can't take the law into your own hands.
话虽这么说 但至少 他干了些他该干的事
Well, at least he's getting something done.
-布鲁斯 快帮我说句话吧 -嗯？
MAN: Bruce, help me out here. - Huh?
哦 我认为 要是一个人 打扮成蝙蝠的模样
Well, a guy who dresses up like a bat clearly has issues.
肯定脑子有问题
But he's put Falcone behind bars.
可他到底把法尔科内关进了监狱 可现在警察却要抓蝙蝠侠 这你怎么看
MAN: Now the cops want him. What does that tell you?
这是他们妒忌他
They're jealous.
先生 喷水池只是用来装饰的...
Sir, the pool is for decoration...
...而且您的朋友没穿泳衣
...and your friends do not have swimwear.
哦 他们是欧洲人 比较开放
Well, they're European.
我不得不要求您离开
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
-这不是钱的问题 -不过 嗯...
- It is not a question of money. - Well, you see...
...我正在买下这个饭店...
...I'm buying this hotel...
...而且我打算重新给 游泳区域定些新的规矩
...and setting some new rules about the pool area.
我觉得应该给蝙蝠侠颁发勋章
I think the Batman deserves a medal.
应该给他穿上紧身衣
And a straitjacket to pin it on.
谢谢
MAN: Thank you.
布鲁斯？
Bruce?
雷切尔？
Rachel?
我听说你回来了
I'd heard you were back.
你在干什么呢？
What are you doing?
在这游泳 哦 很高兴再见面
Just swimming here. Wow, it is good to see you.
你走了很长时间
You were gone a long time.
-我知道 你怎么样？ -老样子
- I know. How are things? - The same.
工作越来越不好做了
Job's getting worse.
一个人的力量是无法改变世界的
Can't change the world on your own.
我还能有有什么其它的选择...
What choice do I have...
...连你都在忙着游泳
...when you're too busy swimming?
雷切尔 这些--
Rachel, all of...
所有这些....
All this...
-- 都不是我 其实 我....
It's... It's not me. It's...
内心 ...
Inside, I am...
有苦衷
I am more.
来 布鲁斯 快点
WOMAN 1: Come on, Bruce. Come on.
布鲁斯 来 我们还要去买下更多的饭店
WOMAN 2: Bruce, we have some more hotels for you to buy.
布鲁斯...
Bruce...
...也许你仍然是那个出色的男孩
...deep down you may still be that same great kid you used to be.
但是这不是你过去如何的问题...
But it's not who you are underneath...
...重要的是你现在的表现
...it's what you do that defines you.
谢谢你能来 克兰医生
WOMAN: Dr. Crane, thanks for coming.
别客气 他割脉了？
Not at all. He cut his wrists?
也许是为了保外就医 但一旦发生任何意外的话...
Probably looking for the insanity plea. But if anything should happen...
那当然 安全第一
Of course, better safe than sorry.
啊 克兰医生 我再也受不了了 太可怕了
Yeah, Dr. Crane, I can't take it anymore. It's all too much.
四面的墙壁像我压呀 压呀 压过来
The walls are closing in. Blah, blah, blah.
吃了好几天这种伙食 我不疯才怪呢
A couple of days of this food, it'll be true.
-你现在想怎么办？ -我现在想知道...
- What do you want? - I wanna know...
...你到底打算怎样让我保持沉默
...how you're gonna convince me to keep my mouth shut.
为什么事呢？ 你什么也不知道
About what? You don't know anything.
我知道你不想让警察过多地了解 他们起获的那些毒品
I know you don't want the cops to take a closer look at the drugs they seized.
我还知道你在你的精神病院里 用病人作的那些药物试验
And I know about your experiments with the inmates of your nut house.
你瞧 我从不跟 我不了解背景的人合作
See, I don't go into business with a guy without finding out his dirty secrets.
还有你雇用的那些打手
And those goons you used.
我掌握着这座城市所有的罪犯
I own the muscle in this town.
目前 我已经帮你 走私药品好几个月了...
Now, I've been bringing your stuff in for months...
...不管你的老板在计划什么 反正是桩大买卖 而我要加入
...so whatever he's planning, it's big, and I want in.
那么 你就知道他要说什么啦
Well, I already know what he'll say.
我们应该干掉你
That we should kill you.
就是他也不能把我怎么样 至少在这不能
Even he can't get me in here. Not in my town.
你想看看我的面罩吗？
Would you like to see my mask?
我用来做药物试验的
I use it in my experiments.
对你这样的人恐怕并不怎么可怕
Now, I'm probably not very frightening to a guy like you.
不过我想对那些警察 他们受不了这种疯狂
But these crazies, they can't stand it.
那么那些家伙是什么表现?
So when did the nut take over the nut house?
[叫喊声]
[SCREAMING]
稻草人:他们又哭又叫的...
SCARECROW: They scream and they cry...
...就像你现在这样
...much as you're doing now.
看来 他并不是假装的
Well, he's not faking. Not that one.
我得去跟法官谈谈 看我是否可以把他...
I'll talk to the judge and see if I can get him moved...
...带回阿克汉姆 在这里我无法给他治疗
...to the secure wing at Arkham. I can't treat him here.
蝙蝠侠:暴风雨就要来了
BATMAN: Storm's coming.
你打败了法尔科内 把警长气疯啦
The scum is getting jumpy because you stood up to Falcone.
这刚开个头 你的搭档当时也在码头
It's a start. Your partner was at the docks with Falcone.
不错 他的第二职业 是充当个小打手
Well, he moonlights as a low-level enforcer.
他们把货物分成两份 只有一半是给毒贩子的
They were splitting the shipment in two. Only half went to the dealers.
为什么？那另一半呢？
Why? What about the other half?
-福拉斯知道 -他不会说的
- Flass knows. - He won't talk.
他会跟我说的
He'll talk to me.
戈登: 雷波特派员 组织了大量的警力要抓捕你
GORDON: Commissioner Loeb set up a massive task force to catch you.
-他认为你很危险 那你怎么认为呢？
- He thinks you're dangerous. - What do you think?
我认为你再给我们提供帮助
I think you're trying to help.
我以前误解你了
But I've been wrong before.
[雷声]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[警笛声]
[SIRENS WAILING]
福拉斯:快点 快点
FLASS: Come on, I ain't got all night.
福拉斯  我还要养活孩子呢
Flass, I have kids to feed.
怎么 他们不喜欢三明治吗？
What, they don't like falafel?
[喊叫声]
[SCREAMING]
另外那些毒品送到哪儿去了？
Where were the other drugs going?
我根本就不知道 我不知道
I never knew. I don't know.
-我向上帝发誓 我不知道 -还是向我发誓吧
- I swear to God. - Swear to me!
[喊叫声]
[SCREAMING]
我不 -- 我不知道 我根本就不知道 真的
I don't... I don't know. I never knew. Never.
他们先送到某人那里放几天 然后再送给毒贩子
They went to some guy for a couple days before they went to the dealers.
为什么？
Why?
那里面　有些其他的东西...
There was something... Something else in the drugs...
-...别人不知道的东西 -什么东西？
...something hidden. - What?
我从来没去过最终的送货地点 是在窄岛
I never went to the drop-off point. It was in the Narrows.
-警察不敢单个进入那个地区 -我像警察吗？
- Cops only go there in force. - Do I look like a cop?
不要--!
No...!
芬奇:我说的就是这个
FINCH: This is the one I'm talking about.
-什么事？ -它不应该在这里
- What's your problem with it? - It shouldn't exist.
这个货船离开新加坡时承载的是 ２６６吨的货柜
This ship left Singapore with 246 containers, but arrived with 247.
而现在是２６７吨 这里边肯定有问题啊
I'm guessing there's something I'm not supposed to find in there.
听着　长官　我们从来不打听 法尔科内先生都运了些什么货
Listen, counselor, we don't wanna know what's in Mr. Falcone's crate.
现在变了　把它打开
Things are working a little differently now. Open it up.
芬奇:这他妈的是什么？
FINCH: What the hell is this?
[枪声]
[GUNSHOTS]
就是你　对不对 大家都在谈论你
It's you, isn't it? Everybody's been talking about you.
快进来
MAN: Get in here!
他们肯定不相信
The other kids won't believe me.
[开门声]
[DOOR OPENS]
销毁所有痕迹
Get rid of all traces.
那还不如烧掉 克兰:也好
MAN: Better torch the whole place. CRANE: All right.
[玻璃破碎声]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
稻草人:怎么　有问题吗？
SCARECROW: Having trouble?
坐吧　喝点水
Take a seat. Have a drink.
看来你太自以为是了
You look like a man who takes himself too seriously.
想听我的建议吗？ 你需要放松一下
Do you want my opinion? You need to lighten up.
[呻吟声]
[GROANING]
艾尔弗雷德　来帮忙
Alfred, help me.
放血　有毒　放血　有毒
Blood. Take. Take poison. Blood poison.
有毒　有毒
Poisonous. Poisonous.
托马斯:布鲁斯...
THOMAS: Bruce...
...怎么掉下去的？
...why do we fall?
-我昏迷了多久？ -两天
- How long was I out? - Two days.
今天是你的生日
It's your birthday.
生日快乐转运
Many happy returns.
我以前有过这种反应 不过这次更强烈
I've felt these effects before, but this was so much more potent.
像是一种气雾致幻化学武器
It was some kind of hallucinogen, weaponized, in aerosol form.
你进错俱乐部了吧　韦恩先生
You have been hanging out in the wrong clubs, Mr. Wayne.
头一天情况不太好 所以我把福克斯先生叫来了
I called Mr. Fox when your condition worsened after the first day.
福克斯:我给你做了血检...
FOX: I analyzed your blood...
...分离受体化合物 以及蛋白基催化物
...isolating the receptor compounds and the protein-based catalyst.
我有必要懂这些专业术语吗？
Am I meant to understand any of that?
不必要　我只想让你 明白这有多复杂
Not at all. I just wanted you to know how hard it was.
-总之　我合成了一种解毒药 -你能在多做些吗？
- Bottom line, I synthesized an antidote. - Could you make more?
你想再过过瘾吗？　韦恩先生
You planning on gassing yourself again, Mr. Wayne?
我说　你知道怎么回事 晚上出去打架的时候...
Well, you know how it is. You're out at night, looking for kicks...
...说不定又被人用迷幻药下暗手...
...someone's passing around the weaponized hallucinogens...
我把剩下的拿来 已经注射的解毒剂已经起效了
I'll bring what I have. The antidote should inoculate you for now.
艾尔弗雷德　很高兴见到你
Alfred, always a pleasure.
卢修斯
Lucius.
-真的不进来吗？ -我得回去了
- You sure you don't want to come in? - I have to get back.
-我只想把这个留下 -谢谢你
- I wanted to leave this. - Thank you.
布鲁斯:雷切尔？
BRUCE: Rachel?
雷切尔:看来有人在连轴转哪
RACHEL: Looks like someone's been burning the candle at both ends.
-你是不是很累呀？ -我过生日
- Must've been quite an occasion. - It is my birthday.
我知道 抱歉我今晚来不了了 我只是把礼物送过来
I know. I'm sorry I can't come tonight. I was just dropping off your present.
-晚上有更好的安排吗？ -我的上司失踪两天了...
- You've got better plans? - My boss has been missing for days...
...这种情况就意味着我应该...
...which means I should probably start by looking...
-...去河里打捞他 -雷切尔.
...at the bottom of the river. - Rachel.
[手机响]
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
-雷切尔 -不好意思
RACHEL: Excuse me.
雷切尔.道斯
Rachel Dawes.
谁给他这权力 把克兰马上带到办公室 不许他说不
Who authorized that? Get Crane down there now. Don't take no for an answer.
给莱曼医生打电话 告诉他明天一早 把自己的评估报告放在法官的办公桌上
Call Dr. Lehmann, tell him we need our own assessment to the judge by morning.
-出什么事了？ -是法尔科内.
- What's wrong? - It's Falcone.
克兰医生把他带到 阿克汉姆精神病院去了
Dr. Crane moved him to Arkham Asylum on suicide watch.
你现在要去阿克汉姆吗？ 那可是在窄岛上呀 雷切尔
You're going to Arkham now? It's in the Narrows, Rachel.
你过你的生日吧 布鲁斯
You enjoy your party, Bruce.
-我们可有工作要做了 -多加小心
- Some of us have work to do. - You be careful.
-生日快乐 纸条书
Happy birthday.
但是 韦恩少爷 客人们马上就要到了
But, Master Wayne, the guests will be arriving.
我回来之前 想办法让他们高兴
Keep them happy until I arrive.
把你知道的笑话讲给他们听
Tell them that joke you know.
[钢琴声]
[PLAYING PIANO]
厄尔:玩得挺高兴吗？
EARLE: Having fun?
厄尔？你这个大人物 来这种地方干什么？
Bill? Now, what's a big shot like you doing in a place like this?
我想知道些资料
I need some information.
韦恩企业产品47-B 1-ME.
The Wayne Enterprise 47-B, 1 -ME.
1-ME.
1 -ME.
是微波发射器 设计的目的是为了蒸发敌人的供水系统
It's a microwave emitter. It was designed to vaporize an enemy's water supply.
据说他们曾经用亲水化学介质作测试...
Rumor was they tested dispersing water-based chemicals into the air...
...可这样做是不是违法的？
...but isn't that illegal?
我需要所有这个研发项目的...
I want all the information on the development of this project...
...所有数据 档案和背景资料
...all data, files, backup disks, on my desk right away.
都说全了？
Did you lose one?
我把你的部门合并到档案部
I'm merging your department with Archives.
同时 我把你解雇了
And I am firing you.
你看见我给你的备忘录吗？
Didn't you get the memo?
法尔科内:稻草人
FALCONE: Scarecrow.
稻草人
Scarecrow.
道斯小姐 这很反常
Miss Dawes, this is most irregular.
我对已经交给法官的报告 没有任何补充了
I have nothing to add to the report I filed with the judge.
-我对你的报告有疑问 -举个例子
- I have questions about your report. - Such as?
对于一个52岁从无精神病史的男人来说...
Isn't it convenient for a 52-year-old man who has no history of mental illness...
...在被起诉的时候突然之间精神崩溃 这也太不说得过去了吧
...to have a psychotic breakdown just when he's about to be indicted?
是啊 正如你自己亲眼所见 他的症状实在是太说不过去了
As you can see for yourself, there is nothing convenient about his symptoms.
-稻草人. -什么"稻草人 "?.
- Scarecrow. - What's "scarecrow"?
病人通常会被某种幻觉所控制...
Patients suffering delusional episodes often focus their paranoia...
...外在表现痛苦...
...on an external tormentor...
...通常会寄托一种原型
...usually one conforming to Jungian archetypes.
而在他身上，就是稻草人
In this case, a scarecrow.
-他服药了吗？ -精神病药理学是我的第一专业
- He's drugged? - Psychopharmacology is my primary field.
克兰 [无线电上] : 我是药物的坚决拥护者
CRANE [ON RADIO]: I'm a strong advocate.
在外边他是强人
Outside, he was a giant.
在这里 只有意识才是强者
In here, only the mind can grant you power.
你更愿意颠倒过来
You enjoy the reversal.
我更推崇意识超过生理
I respect the mind's power over the body.
这也使我选择我的工作的原因
It's why I do what I do.
我选择的工作就是把法尔科内 这样的恶棍关进监狱 而不是精神病院
I do what I do to keep thugs like Falcone behind bars, not in therapy.
我需要我们自己的精神病学医生 对法尔科内做更全面的检查...
I want my own psychiatric consultant to have full access to Falcone...
..包括他的血液 查出你给他用了什么药
...including blood work. Find out what exactly you put him on.
-明天一早再说 -就今晚
- First thing tomorrow, then. - Tonight.
我已经通知康提总院的莱曼医生了
I've already paged Dr. Lehmann at County General.
克兰:随你的便吧
CRANE: As you wish.
这边请
This way, please.
有些东西你应该看一看
There's something I think you should see.
这里是我们制药的地方
This is where we make the medicine.
也许你应该来点 给你醒醒脑
Perhaps you should have some, clear your head.
[喊叫声]
[SCREAMING]
有谁知道你来这？
Who knows you're here?
谁知道？
Who knows?
他来了
He's here.
谁？
MAN 1: Who?
蝙蝠侠
The Batman.
咱们怎么办？ -发现小偷后...
MAN 1: What do we do? - What anyone does...
...一般人都怎么办？
...when a prowler comes around.
-报警 -你想把警察招来？
- Call the police. - You want the cops here?
现在他们不能阻止我们
At this point, they can't stop us.
但是蝙蝠侠老喜欢捣乱
But the Batman has a talent for disruption.
我们把他逼到外面去 警察自然会逮住他 走
Force him outside, the police will take him down. Go.
他怎么办？ 克兰:她坚持不了多久
MAN 1: What about her? CRANE: She hasn't got long.
我给了他超浓缩的剂量
I gave her a concentrated dose.
意识再强也撑不了多久 现在走吧
The mind can only take so much. Now go.
他们传说的是真的吗？
MAN 2: The things they say about him.
他真会飞吗？
Can he really fly?
我听说他会隐身
MAN 3: I heard he can disappear.
好吧 咱们这就会知道的
Well, we'll find out.
对不对？
Won't we?
[枪声]
[GUNSHOTS]
尝尝自己的药吧 医生
Taste of your own medicine, doctor?
你都在这搞了什么鬼？
What have you been doing here?
你在为谁工作？
Who are you working for?
拉 -- 拉.阿勒古尔
Ra's... Ra's al Ghul.
拉.阿勒古尔已经死了 到底为谁工作？
Ra's al Ghul is dead. Who are you working for?
克兰
Crane.
克兰医生现在不在
Dr. Crane isn't here right now.
如果你愿意约定的话....
But if you'd like to make an appointment...
[警笛声]
[SIRENS WAILING]
蝙蝠侠 放下武器 出来投降
OFFICER [OVER P.A.]: Batman, put down your weapons and surrender.
你被包围了
You're surrounded.
-你们还等什么呢？ -等后援
- What are you waiting for? - Backup.
-后援？ -蝙蝠侠在里面
- Backup? - The Batman's in there.
SWAT马上就要到了...
SWAT's on the way. But if you wanna go in now...
...你要是进去我会跟着你的 先生
...I'll be right behind you, sir.
SWAT已经出发了
SWAT's on the way.
-嘿 -嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
戈登:她怎么了？
GORDON: What's happened to her?
克兰给她喷了一种毒药 能引起恐惧的致幻剂
Crane poisoned her with a psychotropic hallucinogen, a panic-inducing toxin.
-我带她去急救 -他们救不了他，我能
- Let me get her down to the medics. - They can't help her, but I can.
带她下楼 在后巷里等我
Get her downstairs. Meet me in the alley.
克兰把致毒剂需要的化学品 藏在法尔科内的货里偷运进来...
Crane's been smuggling his toxin hidden in Falcone's drugs...
...打算投在城市的供水系统里
...and they're dumping it into the water supply.
-他到底想干什么？ -我不清楚
- What was he planning? - I don't know.
他为法尔科内工作吗？
Was he working for Falcone?
他提到了另一个人 一个更恶的人
He mentioned someone else, someone worse.
我要赶在毒剂对她 造成永久伤害前给她解毒
She needs the antidote before the damage is permanent.
-她还能坚持多久？ -没多久了
- How long does she have? - Not long.
[嗡嗡声]
[BUZZING IN DISTANCE]
什么声音？
What is that?
-援军到了 -这是什么？
- Backup. - What the...?
[蝙蝠啸叫声]
[BATS SQUEAKING]
打搅了
Excuse me.
蝙蝠侠:她怎么样？ -晕过去了 咱们得赶快走
BATMAN: How is she? - She's fading. We gotta go.
我去开车
I'll get my car.
蝙蝠侠:我有开车来
BATMAN: I brought mine.
你的车？
Yours?
我也要弄一辆这样的
I've gotta get me one of those.
他上了一辆交通工具
OFFICER 1: He is in a vehicle.
车？什么颜色？
OFFICER 2 [OVER RADIO]: Make and color?
一辆黑色的...
It's a black...
...坦克
...tank.
镇静
Stay calm.
你中毒了
You've been poisoned.
我跟着他
I'm on him.
稳住呼吸
Breathe slowly.
坐稳了
Hold on.
-你在干什么 -抄近路
- What are you doing? - Shortcut.
[无线电]:空中呼叫地面 他被堵住了
OFFICER 3 [OVER RADIO]: Air One to ground, block that ramp.
他在房顶没地跑了
He's got no way off that roof.
关闭发动机 从车上下来
Turn off your engine. Step away from the car.
-相信我 电脑:武器系统就绪
- Trust me. COMPUTER: Weapons system activated.
这家伙是谁？
Who is this guy?
[无线电]:他往哪去啦？
OFFICER 2 [OVER RADIO]: Where's he going?
他在屋顶上
He's on the roof.
-他走到哪条街？ -他不是在街上
OFFICER 2: What street is he taking? - He's not on a street.
他在屋顶上飞呢
He's flying on rooftops.
至少告诉我那车什么样？
At least tell me what it looks like.
不用了
Never mind.
我看见它了
Got him.
我们追上他了
Coming right up on his butt.
我们在I-17大道向西追踪可疑车辆
OFFICER 3: We're tracking suspect vehicle heading west on l- 17.
-空中一号呼叫地面 -丢失目标
- Air One to ground. - I lost him.
我们失去目标 9号出口已封锁
OFFICER 3: We've lost visual. Exit 9 is blocked.
我们掉头再去搜寻其它街道
We'll loop back to check the frontage road.
电脑:潜行功能开启
COMPUTER: Stealth mode activated.
坚持住
Stay with me.
什么？它在那
What...? There he is.
千万坚持住
Just hold on.
雷切尔!
Rachel!
给韦恩少爷 福克斯送
GORDON: They get any of this into the mains?
戈登:他们把这些毒剂 投放到供水系统没有？
OFFICER: Yeah.
投了
Notify the water company. There's gotta be a way to isolate it.
通知自来水公司 隔离那些还没有投放的区域
No. They put it all in. They must've been at this for weeks.
他们在所有地点都投放了 肯定已经持续了好几个星期了
- Gotham's entire water supply is laced. - Why haven't we felt the effects?
-哥特的供水系统都已经被污染了 -为什么我们没有反应？
Must be a compound that has to be absorbed through the lungs.
一定要进入呼吸道才有作用
[BATS SQUEAKING]
[蝙蝠啸叫声]
BATMAN: How do you feel?
蝙蝠侠:你感觉如何？
Where are we?
我们这是在哪？
- Why did you bring me here? - lf I hadn't, your mind would be lost.
-怎么把我带到这来？ -我要不这么做你就丧失意识了
- You were poisoned. - It was...
-你中毒了 -是--
- It was Dr. Crane. - Rest. Gordon has Crane.
-是克兰医生 -放心吧，戈登已经抓住了克兰
Is Sergeant Gordon your friend?
戈登警官是你的朋友嘛？
I don't have the luxury of friends.
拥有朋友对我来说太奢侈了
I'm gonna give you a sedative. You'll wake up back at home.
我给你注射镇静剂 等你醒来时就在自己家里了
When you do, get these to Gordon, and Gordon alone. Trust no one.
你把这些交给戈登 亲自交给 他本人 不要相信任何人
- What are they? - The antidote.
-是什么？ -是抗体
One for Gordon to inoculate himself, the other for mass production.
一份给戈登 其它的用来大量生产
RACHEL: Mass production?
雷切尔:大量生产
Crane was just a pawn. We need to be ready.
克兰不过是个小卒 我们必须做好准备
When you told me your grand plan for saving Gotham...
当你跟我说要拯救哥特城的时候...
...all that stopped me from calling the men in white coats...
...我之所以没有叫穿白大褂的人...
...was when you said it wasn't about thrill-seeking.
...就是因为你说了一句话 说你这不是寻找刺激
- It's not. - What would you call that?
-确实不是 -那你把这叫什么？
- Damn good television. - It's a miracle no one was killed.
-该死的电视 -居然无人受伤 真是奇迹
I didn't have time to observe the rules of the road, Alfred.
我当时没时间遵守交规了 艾尔弗雷德
You're getting lost inside this monster of yours.
你已经被你内心的野兽冲昏了头
I'm using this monster to help other people, just like my father did.
我在利用这支野兽帮助其它的人 就像我父亲当年做的一样
For Thomas Wayne, helping others...
对于托马斯.韦恩来说 帮助其它人...
...wasn't about proving anything to anyone, including himself.
...并不意味着向别人证明什么 包括他自己
It's Rachel, Alfred. She was dying.
是为了雷切尔 艾尔弗雷德 她当时要死了
She's downstairs, sedated. I need you to take her home.
现在她在楼下 注射了镇静剂 你送她回家吧
Well, we both care for Rachel, but what you're doing has to be beyond that.
我们都关心雷切尔 可你做的已经超越了这一点
It can't be personal, or you're just a vigilante.
不是针对她一个人 或者你就是个义务警员
- Is Fox still here? - Yes, sir.
-福克斯在吗？ -在 先生
We need to send these people away.
咱们该把那些客人送走了
Those are Bruce Wayne's guests. You have a name to maintain.
那些可都是布鲁斯.韦恩的朋友 你要注意名声
I don't care about my name.
我才不在乎名声呢
It's not just your name, sir. It's your father's name.
不止是你的名声 还有您父亲的
And it's all that's left of him.
这是他留下的一切
Don't destroy it.
不要毁了他
[GUESTS SINGING "HAPPY BIRTHDAY"]
[客人们唱生日歌]
- Mr. Earle. - Happy birthday, Bruce.
-厄尔先生 -生日快乐 布鲁斯.
Thank you.
谢谢
How did the stock offering go?
股票上市情况如何？
Prices soared.
市值相当高
Who was buying?
谁在买？
All kinds of funds and brokerages.
各种基金会和经纪公司
It's a bit technical.
这么说技术上有点难懂
The key thing is...
总而言之...
...our company's future is secure.
...我们企业的未来是有保障的了
Great.
太棒了
A little the worse for wear, I'm afraid.
没事的 她喝多了
GORDON: What was the plan, Crane?
戈登:计划到底是什么？克兰？
How were you gonna get your toxin into the air?
你打算怎样把你的毒剂 释放到空气中
Scarecrow. Scarecrow.
稻草人. 稻草人.
Who were you working for, Crane?
你在为谁工作 克兰？
Oh, it's too late.
已经太晚了
You can't stop it now.
你已经无法阻止这一切
GORDON: Here.
戈登:过来
MAN: Happy birthday, Bruce. - Thank you. Thanks.
生日快乐 布鲁斯. -谢谢你 谢谢
And thank you for that item.
还有你送我的那些东西
You're welcome.
别客气
- I know you'll put it to good use. - I already have.
-我知道你会好好利用它的 -已经好好利用了
How long would it take to manufacture on a large scale?
大规模生产的话需要多长时间？
Weeks. Why?
几个星期 怎么了？
Somebody's planning to disperse the toxin using the water supply.
有人打算利用供水系统 大范围投放致幻剂
The water supply won't help you disperse an inhalant.
这样做无法感染呼吸系统
What?
什么？
Unless you have a microwave emitter powerful enough...
除非使用大功率的微波蒸发器...
...to vaporize all the water in the mains.
...是被污染的水全部蒸发
A microwave emitter like the one Wayne Enterprises just misplaced.
就像韦恩企业刚刚失窃的那种微波蒸发器一样
Misplaced?
失窃的？
Earle just fired me for asking too many questions about it.
厄尔开除了我 就是因为我问的问题多
Go back to Wayne Enterprises now and start making more of that antidote.
我需要你立即返回韦恩企业 开始生产尽可能多的解毒剂
The police are gonna need as much as they can get their hands on.
我认为警察很快就会有 大量的需求的
My security clearance has been revoked.
我的出入证已经被吊销了
That wouldn't stop a man like you, would it?
我认为这点事难不到你吧？
I suppose not.
应该是吧
- Bruce, there's somebody you must meet. - Not now, Mrs. Delane.
-布鲁斯 有个人想见见你 你有时间吗？ -现在不行 德林夫人
Now, am I pronouncing this right...
那么 我的念法对吗？...
...Mr. Ra's al Ghul?
...拉.阿勒古尔先生
You're not Ra's al Ghul.
你不是拉.阿勒古尔
I watched him die.
我亲眼看见他死的
DUCARD: But is Ra's al Ghul immortal?
杜卡德:可拉.阿勒古尔不是不朽的吗？
Are his methods supernatural?
他的意念不是超越现实的吗？
Or cheap parlor tricks to conceal your true identity, Ra's?
或者简单的易容术就能隐藏起 你的真实面目把 杜卡德
Surely a man who spends his nights scrambling over the rooftops of Gotham...
当然了 一个半夜里到处爬屋顶的人...
...wouldn't begrudge me dual identities.
...恐怕不会抱怨我的双重身份吧？
I saved your life.
我救了你的命
I warned you about compassion, Bruce.
我提醒过你不能怜悯 布鲁斯
Your quarrel is with me.
你是冲着我来的吧？
You let these people go.
让这些客人走吧
You are welcome to explain the situation to them.
那就麻烦你给他们解释一下吧
BRUCE: Everyone.
布鲁斯:诸位
Everybody?
诸位
I...
我...
I want to thank you all for coming here tonight and drinking all of my booze.
我很感谢大家今晚能 出席我的生日宴会喝光了我的酒
[GUESTS LAUGHING]
[笑声]
No, really.
不 真的
There's a thing about being a Wayne...
作为韦恩家族的一员我知道...
...that you're never short of a few freeloaders, like yourselves...
...身边少不了骗吃骗喝的人，就像你们...
...to fill up your mansion with. So here's to you people. Thank you.
...也只是为了撑场面凑人数 为了诸位干杯 谢谢你们
- That's enough, Bruce. - I'm not finished.
-太过分了 布鲁斯. -我还没说完
To all of you...
为你们这些....
All of you phonies, all of you two-faced friends...
所有这些虚伪的家伙 所有这些两面三刀的朋友...
...you sycophantic suck-ups who smile through your teeth at me...
...所有这些阿谀奉承之人 以及势力的小人们...
...please, leave me in peace.
...请你们让我清静清静吧
Please go.
请你们走吧
Stop smiling, it's not a joke. Please leave.
收起你们的假笑吧 我并不是开玩笑 请大家离开吧
The party's over, get out.
宴会结束了 现在滚吧
The apple has fallen very far from the tree, Mr. Wayne.
韦恩先生 你与你的 父母真是天壤之别
He's turning into a jerk.
他怎么变得这么古怪了
Amusing.
有意思
But pointless. None of these people have long to live.
但是无济于事 这些人都活不长了
Your antics at the asylum have forced my hand.
你的解毒药迫使我提前出手
So Crane was working for you.
这么说克兰是为你工作
His toxin is derived from the organic compound found in our blue flowers.
他的致幻剂是从我们的 蓝色花朵里提炼出来的
He was able to weaponize it.
他把它制成了武器
He's not a member of the League of Shadows?
他并不是影子同盟的成员
Of course not. He thought our plan was to hold the city to ransom.
当然不是 他以为我们要用致幻剂要挟政府呢
But really, you are gonna release Crane's poison on the entire city.
可你打算用克兰的毒剂污染整个城市
Then watch Gotham tear itself apart through fear.
然后欣赏整个哥特城陷入恐惧和毁灭的景象
BRUCE: You're gonna destroy millions of lives.
布鲁斯:你要毁掉几百万人的生命
DUCARD: Only a cynical man would call what these people have "lives," Wayne.
杜卡德:只有疯子才把这些人的生命当回事 韦恩
Crime. Despair.
罪恶 绝望
This is not how man was supposed to live.
人类的生活不该是这个样
The League of Shadows has been a check against human corruption...
影子同盟致力于缉查人类的腐败...
...for thousands of years.
...已历经千年
We sacked Rome. Loaded trade ships with plague rats.
我们毁灭了罗马 货船把鼠疫带到了世界各个角落
Burned London to the ground.
还把伦敦烧成了残垣断壁
Every time a civilization reaches the pinnacle of its decadence...
每一次文明一旦陷入腐败的泥沼...
...we return to restore the balance.
...我们就会出来维持平衡
Gotham isn't beyond saving.
哥特城还没有沦落到 不可救药的地步
Give me more time. There are good people here.
给我点时间 这里还有不少好人
You're defending a city so corrupt...
你要保护的城市...
...we have infiltrated every level of its infrastructure.
...我们已经渗透到社会的每一个阶层
Time to play.
游戏时间到了
When I found you in that jail, you were lost.
我在监狱里见到你的时候 你很迷失低落
But I believed in you.
但是现在 我恢复了对你的信心
I took away your fear, and I showed you a path.
我消除了你的恐惧 给你指明了出路
You were my greatest student.
你是我的得意门生
It should be you standing by my side, saving the world.
你应该站在我这一边 拯救世界
I'll be standing where I belong.
我将站在我该属于的一方
Between you and the people of Gotham.
站在你和哥特城人们中间
No one can save Gotham.
谁也救不了哥特城
When a forest grows too wild, a purging fire is inevitable and natural.
当森林生长得过于茂盛的时候 一场大火的降临是再自然不过的
Tomorrow the world will watch in horror as its greatest city destroys itself.
明天 世界将共同瞩目 这个伟大的城市自己毁灭自己
The movement back to harmony will be unstoppable this time.
平衡的运动是不可阻挡的
- You attacked Gotham before? - Of course.
-以前你袭击过哥特城吗？ -当然
Over the ages our weapons have grown more sophisticated.
经过长时间的发展 我们的武器越来越先进
With Gotham we tried a new one. Economics.
在哥特城 我们采用 一种新型武器 经济
But we underestimated certain of Gotham's citizens...
但是我却低估了哥特城的一些市民...
...such as your parents.
...比如你的父母
Gunned down by one of the very people they were trying to help.
结果他们被他们一心要救助的人枪杀了
Create enough hunger and everyone becomes a criminal.
无处不在的饥饿使人人变成了罪犯
Their deaths galvanized the city into saving itself...
他们的死摧毁了这个城市的自救之心...
...and Gotham has limped on ever since.
...至此哥特城就一蹶不振了
We are back to finish the job.
我们这次来就是了结这一切的
And this time no misguided idealists will get in the way.
而这一次绝对不会有不得要领的理想主义者了
Like your father, you lack the courage to do all that is necessary.
跟你父母一样 你缺乏不惜一切代价的勇气
If someone stands in the way of true justice...
如果有人阻挡正义的实现...
...you simply walk up behind them and stab them in the heart.
...就应该从他们的背后狠狠地捅上一刀
- I am gonna stop you. - You never did learn...
-我要阻止你 -你还没学会...
...to mind your surroundings.
...眼观六路耳听八方
Justice is balance.
正义是公平的
You burned my house and left me for dead.
你曾经烧了我的房子 和置我于死地
Consider us even.
这下扯平了
No one comes out. Make sure.
不许任何人出来 明白？
GORDON: They're all gone?
戈登:人都跑了
- How many from maximum security? - Every one of them.
-重点看护区跑了多少 -都跑了
Serial killers, rapists.
连环杀手 强奸犯
Raise the bridges. We don't want any getting off the island.
把吊桥吊起来 不能让他们逃离这个岛
FLASS: Yeah, I'll raise the bridges...
福拉斯:好 我去吊吊桥...
...when I get every available unit out here to catch the homicidal maniacs...
...我先去调集所有能调集的人马...
...that are running loose out there. - Come on!
-...一起来这里抓那些逃出去的疯子 -快去吧
I hope you're not a member of the fire brigade.
但愿你不是消防队的
Master Wayne! Master Wayne!
韦恩少爷！韦恩少爷！
What is the point of all those pushups if you can't even lift a bloody log?
你平时做的俯卧撑都白做了 连块木头都搬不动
[PLAYING PIANO]
[钢琴声]
BRUCE: What have I done, Alfred?
布鲁斯:我都干了些什么呀？艾尔弗雷德
Everything my family...
我家的一切...
...my father, built...
...我父亲亲手建造的....
The Wayne legacy is more than bricks and mortar, sir.
韦恩家族的遗产不仅仅是砖瓦 少爷
I wanted to save Gotham.
我只想拯救哥特城
I failed.
但我失败了
Why do we fall, sir?
为什么说失败 少爷？
So that we can learn to pick ourselves up.
我们学会了“哪里摔倒哪里爬起来”
You still haven't given up on me?
你还没对我失去信心？
Never.
永远不会
GORDON: Down!
戈登:给我下来
MAN: Harassment! I see harassment!
强制执法 我是目击证人
Maybe you'd like to see some excessive force?
也许你还想见识见识暴力执法吧
Madman with a gun.
拿枪就了不起呀
WOMAN [ON TV]: With residents furious...
[电视报道]: 民众对大量警察围堵...
...at the unprecedented show of police strength to round up the inmates...
...精神病院病人的行为感到异常愤怒....
We're about to raise these bridges.
吊桥马上起要起吊了
Officer, I am a Gotham City district attorney. Let me pass.
警官 我是检察院的 让我过去吧
- Just shut up! - Hey, Flass, cool it!
-你闭嘴 -嘿 福拉斯 别激动
OFFICER 1: Hold these people back.
把围观者逼退回去
OFFICER 2: Hey, Gordon. Somebody here to see you.
嘿 戈登 有人要见你
- What are you doing here? - Our friend sent me with this.
-你来这干嘛？ -我们的朋友让我给你带来这个
It counteracts Crane's toxin.
它能抵挡克兰的致幻剂
Hopefully you won't need it.
希望你用不着它
Not unless he's got some way of getting that crap into the air.
除非能把它释放到空气中
All right, last one across.
好吧，最后一个
OFFICER 1: People, they want this bridge up in no more than three minutes!
快一点 3分钟之内就要起吊了
Better get you off the island before they raise the bridges. Patrolman!
最好在吊桥升起来之前 把你护送出去 巡警
Go!
走
[PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[模糊的喊声]
I can't find my mom.
我找不到我妈妈了
RACHEL: Hey!
雷切尔:嘿！
What the hell are you doing?
你干什么呢？
DUCARD: Gentlemen...
杜卡德:先生们...
...time to spread the word.
...现在到了传播消息的时候
And the word is...
这个消息就是...
...panic.
...痛苦
Jesus. The pressure, it's spiking.
天哪 压力突然增大了
[BEEPING]
[哔哔声]
Right there.
这
MAN: That water main is right under the Narrows.
主要是窄岛那里
[PEOPLE COUGHING]
[咳嗽声]
RACHEL: It's okay.
雷切尔:好了 没关系
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[模糊的说话声]
This is Commissioner Loeb.
我是雷波特派员
Come on, somebody talk to me.
请答话 请答话
Come on!
请答话！
GORDON: Loeb, Loeb. This is Gordon.
戈登:雷波 雷波 我是戈登
What the hell is going on?
告诉我出什么事了？
We need reinforcements. TAC teams, SWAT, riot cops!
我们需要增援 空军 SWAT 防暴警察
Gordon! All the city's riot police are on the island with you!
戈登! 所有的警察都调到你那里了
GORDON [OVER RADIO]: Well, they're completely incapacitated!
戈登 [无线电中] : 不错 可他们都失去战斗力了
It's okay, it's okay. No one's gonna hurt you.
没事了 没事了 谁也不会伤害到你的 没事的
SCARECROW: Of course they are!
稻草人: 当然啦
- Crane? - No. Scarecrow.
-克兰?. -不 我是稻草人
Gordon...
戈登...
...there's nobody left to send in.
...已经没有人手了
GORDON: So I'm on my own?
戈登:这么说就只能靠我自己了？
The Narrows is tearing itself to pieces.
窄岛已经毁灭得差不多了
This is just the beginning. If they hit the whole city...
这才刚刚开始 如果他们把致幻剂散播到全城的话...
...there's nothing to stop Gotham tearing itself apart.
...那整个哥特城就玩完了
- How are they gonna do that? - The train.
-他们要怎么干？ -他们要利用火车
The monorail follows the water mains to the central hub beneath Wayne Tower.
单轨铁路顺着供水系统可以 一直通向韦恩大厦的中央管道
If the machine gets to the station...
一旦他们把蒸发器放进韦恩火车站...
...it'll cause a chain reaction that'll vaporize the city's water supply.
...必将引起一系列的连锁反应 最终将整个城市的自来水全部蒸发
Covering Gotham in this poison.
整个城市将笼罩在毒气中
I'm gonna stop him from loading that train, but I may need your help.
我去阻止他将武器运上火车 但我可能需要你的帮助
- What do you need? - Can you drive stick?
-你需要什么？ -会开手动挡的车吗？
SCARECROW: There you are!
稻草人:来吧
There is nothing to fear...
没什么可怕的...
...but fear itself!
...只有恐惧本身
I am here to help you!
我是来拯救你们的
[SCARECROW SCREAMING]
[稻草人惨叫声]
Batman will save us. He'll come.
蝙蝠侠会来救我们的 他一定会的
- He'll come. - Don't peek.
-他一定会来的 -别看
This is Gordon. Prepare to lower the bridge.
我是戈登. 准备放吊桥
I told you he'd come.
我告诉过你他会来的
RACHEL: Wait.
雷切尔:等等
You could die.
你可能会丧命的
At least tell me your name.
至少告诉我你的名字
It's not who I am underneath...
这不是我过去如何的问题...
...but what I do that defines me.
...重要的是我现在的表现
Bruce?
布鲁斯?
Well, well. You took my advice about theatricality a bit literally.
可惜呀 可惜 你把我关于 戏剧性的建议表现得过于文学化了
- It ends here. - For you and the police, maybe.
-该结束了 -对你和警察而言 也许如此
My fight, however, lies with the rest of Gotham.
而我的战争 是和哥特城的战争
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a city to destroy.
现在 请原谅 我要去摧毁城市了
- I can't beat two of your pawns? - As you wish.
-我打不过你旁边的两个吗？ -随你的便吧
COMPUTER: GPS online.
电脑:GPS系统启动
In 100 yards.
距离100码
DUCARD: Gentlemen.
杜卡德:先生们
Who the hell authorized this?
到底谁下的命令
COMPUTER: Distance to Wayne Tower, three miles.
电脑:距韦恩大厦三英里
The pressure's moving along the mains, blowing the pipes.
压力沿主管线扩散 雅图管道全部破裂
If that pressure reaches us...
如果压力到达这里...
...the water supply right across the whole city is gonna blow!
...全城的管道就全完了
COMPUTER: At the next intersection, turn right.
电脑:下一个区段右转
You will never learn.
你从不吸取教训
Sorry.
不好意思
- Familiar. Don't you have anything new? - How about this?!
-老套子 你就没有点新鲜的吗？ -这个怎么样？
COMPUTER: You have arrived at Wayne Tower.
电脑:你已经抵达韦恩大厦
MAN: Evacuate the building.
撤离大楼
We're on top of the main hub and it's gonna blow.
我们坐落在上方的主管线 马上就要爆裂了
COMPUTER: Weapons system activated.
电脑:射击系统准备就绪
Nice ride.
好车
COMPUTER: Armed.
电脑:瞄准
[BEEPING]
[哔哔声]
Don't be afraid, Bruce.
别害怕 布鲁斯.
Come on. Come on.
快点 快呀
DUCARD: You are just an ordinary man in a cape.
杜卡德:你不过是个普通人
That's why you couldn't fight injustice, that's why you can't stop this train.
所以你无法与非正义抗衡 所以你无法阻止这列火车
Who said anything about stopping it?
谁说要阻止它？
Yes!
太好了
BATMAN: You never learned to mind your surroundings!
蝙蝠侠:你总是学不会眼观六路耳听八方
Have you finally learned to do what is necessary?
那你最终学会不惜一切代价了吗？
I won't kill you...
我不打算杀死你...
...but I don't have to save you.
...但我也不打算再救你一命
JESSICA: The meeting's already started. - What meeting?
杰西卡:会议已经开始了 -什么会议？
Fox, I seem to remember firing you.
福克斯 我记得我好像 已经把你开除了
You did.
确实如此
I got another job.
我有找到了另一个职位
Yours.
你的职位
On whose authority?
谁任命的
ALFRED: Batman may have made the front page...
艾尔弗雷德: 有关蝙蝠侠的新闻都是头条...
...but Bruce Wayne got pushed to page eight.
...但是有关布鲁斯.韦恩的新闻 只能登在第八页
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
[手机铃声]
Bruce Wayne.
布鲁斯.韦恩
What makes you think you can decide who's running Wayne Enterprises?
你怎么会自己以为自己 有权经营韦恩集团呢?
- The fact that I'm the owner. EARLE: What are you talking about?
-事实上我才是集团的拥有者 厄尔:你说什么?
The company went public a week ago.
集团一周前已经上市了
And I bought most of the shares.
我通过好几个慈善机构和基金会
Through various charitable foundations and trusts and so forth.
购买了大部分的股份
Look, it's all a bit technical, but the important thing...
你瞧 这么说是不是技术上有点难懂 总之最重要的是...
...is that my company's future is secure.
...韦恩集团的未来有了保障
Right, Mr. Fox?
对不对 福克斯?
FOX: Right you are, Mr. Wayne.
福克斯:对 韦恩先生
Didn't you get the memo?
你拿到备忘录了吗?
- I'm sorry I didn't tell you, Rachel. - No. No, Bruce...
-对不起 我没有告诉你 雷切尔 -不不不 布鲁斯...
...I'm sorry.
...应该说对不起的是我
The day that Chill died, I...
切尔死的那一天 我....
I said terrible things.
我说的话太伤人了
But true things.
但确实是实话
I was a coward with a gun...
我是个拿着枪的懦夫...
...and justice is about more than revenge, so thank you.
...正义不仅仅是报仇 所以 我谢谢你
I never stopped thinking about you.
我一直在想着你
About us.
想着我们的事
And when I heard you were back, I...
听说你回来后 我....
I started to hope.
心里又燃起了希望
But then I found out about your mask.
后来我发现了你就是蝙蝠侠
Batman's just a symbol, Rachel.
蝙蝠侠只是一个象征, 雷切尔.
No. This...
不 那是...
...is your mask.
...是你的面具
Your real face is the one that criminals now fear.
现在罪犯们惧怕的是真正的你
The man I loved...
我以前所爱的...
...the man who vanished...
...那个失踪的你...
...he never came back at all.
...根本就没有再回来
But maybe he's still out there somewhere.
也许他就在外面某个地方
Maybe someday, when Gotham no longer needs Batman...
也许有那么一天 当哥特城不再需要蝙蝠侠的时候...
...I'll see him again.
...我又能再见到他
- Proved me wrong, you know. - About what?
-我承认我以前错了 -关于什么?
Your father would be very proud of you.
我是说你的父亲一定会为你感到自豪
Just like me.
就像我一样感到自豪
RACHEL: What will you do?
雷切尔:你打算将来怎么办?
Rebuild it.
重建庄园
Just the way it was, brick for brick.
恢复它从前的一砖一瓦
Just the way it was, sir?
和从前的一模一样?
Yeah, why?
你是什么意思?
I thought this might be a good opportunity for...
我是说这是个难得的机会...
...improving the foundations.
...应该重新完善一下地基
- In the southeast corner? - Precisely, sir.
-你是说东南角？ -对极啦
- Nice. - I couldn't find any mob bosses.
-怎么样？ -我连一个黑帮老大都见不到
BATMAN: Well, sergeant? - It's "lieutenant" now.
蝙蝠侠:是吗？上校 -现在是“中校”了
You really started something.
你干的真不错
Bent cops running scared.
坏警察都闻风丧胆了
Hope on the streets.
街道上也充满了希望
- But? - The Narrows is lost.
-还有呢？ -不过窄岛完了
And we still haven't picked up Crane or half the inmates of Arkham that he freed.
我们还没有抓到克兰 还有被他释放的一大半其他病人
We will.
会抓住他们的
We can bring Gotham back.
我要重建哥特城
- What about escalation? - Escalation?
-犯罪率增加怎么办？ -增加？
We start carrying semiautomatics, they buy automatics.
我们开始用半自动武器时 罪犯们已经用上全自动的了
We start wearing Kevlar, they buy armor-piercing rounds.
而当我们开始穿上防弹服的时候 他们却用起了金属爆裂子弹
- And? - And you're wearing a mask...
-还有吗？ -还有当你带着面具...
...and jumping off rooftops.
...从屋顶上跳下来的时候
Now, take this guy.
琢磨琢磨这家伙
Armed robbery, double homicide.
持枪抢劫犯 双料杀人犯
Got a taste for the theatrical, like you.
喜欢戏剧性 跟你一样
Leaves a calling card.
留下一张牌
I'll look into it.
这件事交给我吧
I never said thank you.
我从未谢过你
And you'll never have to.
没有这个必要